影片压制：木子丁  字幕制作：木子丁
======  NORM  TEAM  ======
主演：加里·格兰特 & 黛博拉·蔻尔
片名：金玉盟（又名：难忘的时刻）
编剧：德莫·戴维斯 & 莱奥·麦卡雷
制片：杰瑞·华德
导演：莱奥·麦卡雷
虽然纽约的股票行情
出现了下跌的迹象…
And so while the New York Stock Exchange
showed signs of restlessness...
但丝毫没必要为这一暂时的现象担心
there was little or no uneasiness
on the part of optimists.
单身汉有个特大的喜讯
美国姑娘们…
Here's good news for you bachelors.
Competition for pretty girls...
崇拜的白马王子
尼基·弗伦迪定下了终身…
will definitely be easier now that
Nickie Ferrante, the big dame hunter...
因而单身汉们追求佳人容易了很多
is going out of circulation.
婚礼的钟声终于要为他敲响了
It'll be wedding bells
for him at long last.
弗伦迪今天从欧洲起程…
Mr. Ferrante is sailing
today from Europe...
洛伊斯·克拉克小姐将在纽约码头
迎接未婚夫的归来
and Miss Lois Clarke will be waiting for him
at the gangplank in New York.
洛伊斯继承的家产 价值600万美元
Lois and her lovely
600 million bucks.
太可观了，她不但嫁妆丰厚
人也是美艳超群
What a deal. Not only all that lettuce,
but a beautiful tomato too.
哇！
Wow!
[意大利语]
据悉，英俊潇洒、欧美瞩目的美男子尼基·弗伦迪
[Man Speaking In Italian]
近期将与美丽的女继承人洛伊斯·克拉克小姐
[Italian]
举行婚礼
这位克拉克小姐
[Italian]
是当今美国最富有的女继承人
拥有600万美元的家产
[Italian]
600万美元的家产？
按意大利里拉计算
[Italian]
相当于70几亿里拉
我的天啦！
Mamma mia!
嗯，本台刚刚收到这样一条传闻
Mm. Here's rather
a choice little tidbit.
尼基·弗伦迪今晚起程…
Nickie Ferrante
sails tonight...
他将返回纽约城…
to enter into matrimony...
与美国实业大亨之一缔结良缘
with one of America's
industrial nobility.
嫁妆十分可观
Rock and gravel, I believe.
女方是洛伊斯…克拉克
It's a Miss Lois, uh... Clarke.
当然
Yes.
还有
Well.
那好，新闻报告完了
Well, uh, there you have it.
- 弗伦迪先生吗？  - 不是
- Signor Ferrante?  - No, no.
- 弗伦迪先生吗？  - 他在船上？
- Signor Ferrante?  - Is he on board?
弗伦迪先生！
Yes.
Signor Ferrante!
弗伦迪先生
Signor Ferrante.
弗伦迪先生？
Signor Ferrante?
我在这儿，小伙子
Boy, here I am.
您就是弗伦迪先生？
请您去接个电话，巴黎来的
Are you signor Ferrante?
I have a telephone call for you from Paris.
弗伦迪先生
请在您的照片上签个字吧…
Mr. Ferrante, would you autograph this...
谢谢你们，我一会儿再签
我得去接个电话，谢谢
That's very kind, but I'm wanted
on the telephone. Thank you.
喂？对，我是弗伦迪
Hello?
Yes, this is Ferrante.
谁来的？哦，接过来
Who's calling?
Oh, put her on.
- 你这畜生  - 你好呀，加布里埃尔
- You beast.  - Hello, Gabriella.
你好呀，加布里埃尔
你少跟我废话
"Hello, Gabriella."
Don't you talk to me.
那你干吗打电话来呢？
Don't talk...
then why did you call me?
你曾经说你爱我
好话都让你说了？
How could you speak of love to me,
say the things you did?
现在你要结婚了！
And you,
about to be married!
你还记得我给你那个香烟盒时
你说的话吗？
You remember what you whispered
when I gave you the cigarette case?
当然记得，亲爱的
我说…我说…
Well, of course, dear.
I said, uh... I said, uh...
喂！喂！
你在听吗，加布里埃尔？
电话好像断了
Hello! Hello! Can you hear me, Gabriella?
I believe we're disconnected.
电话根本没断！
We are not disconnected!
接线员！接线员… 噢，真不像话，接线员！
Operator! Operat...
Oh, this is a shame. Operator!
伪君子！若我手里有把刀…
Hypocrite! I have in my hand a knife...
我就会插在你的背上
and I wish it were
in your back.
嗯
Hm.
你好，弗伦迪先生
我是哈瑟维，尼尔·哈瑟维
Well! Mr. Ferrante.
My name's Hathaway, Ned Hathaway.
- 你好？  - 来欢迎您的
- Really?  - Welcome aboard.
能不能劳您驾 跟我的妹妹和妻子打一会儿桥牌 我们正缺少一个…
I was wondering if you'd care to join my wife,
my sister and me in a game of bridge.
噢，对不起，哈瑟维先生，我打桥牌…
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr. Hathaway,
but I cheat.
习惯作弊
It's an addiction.
对不起
你手上的香烟盒是我的
I beg your pardon.
I think you have my cigarette case.
那我也直说吧，我是个珠宝惯偷
I might as well confess.
I am a jewel thief.
我才不信呢
I don't believe it.
我正想去交给事务长
我是在那…哎
I was returning it to the purser.
I found it in the... ah.
先别急
凭什么说是你的？
Just a moment.
How do I know it's yours?
这个嘛…烟盒里有写给我的赠言
Well... There's an inscription to me on the inside.
是吗
Oh.
“给尼古拉”
"To Nicolo."
噢！原来你就是大名鼎鼎的…
Oh! Don't tell me
you're the famous...
关于你的报道我看多了
《生活画报》上，还有…
I have read so much about you in,
uh, Life and Look and...
还有《好管家》上？
可以把盒还给我吗？
Possibly Good Housekeeping?
Now, may I have my case?
- 哦不不，等一等  - 嗯
- No, no. Just a moment.  - Hm.
哇！关系可不一般啦
Whew! This is
frightfully intimate.
遗憾的是我的法语不行
I know just enough French
to be embarrassed.
你能不能简略一点儿
告诉我写的是什么？
Could you, um, refine it a little
and tell me in effect what it says?
那好吧，那上面说…呃…
Well, in effect, it says, uh...
“加布里埃尔号上的三个难忘之夜留念”…
"In memory of three unforgettable nights
aboard La Gabriella"...
她的私人游艇
which is her yacht.
看来还真是你的
I guess that's you, all right.
你是不是写过“我不再微笑”这首歌？
Tell me, did you write the song,
"I'll Never Smile Again"?
没有
No.
但我在考虑写一首
叫“月色笼罩加布里埃尔号”
But I'm thinking of writing one called
"Moon Over La Gabriella."
您认为幽会能代替晚场棒球赛吗？
Do you think it will ever take the place
of night baseball?
不会的
No.
请等一等
Please wait.
我遇到了很大的麻烦
I'm in trouble,
serious trouble.
噢 到处幽会当然会出现麻烦
可怜的姑娘
Well, I could've told you.
Playing around yachts. The poor thing.
- 我想跟你谈谈  - 这种事我可不太擅长
- I must talk with someone.  - Well, I'm not very good at that sort of thing.
我曾经很健谈，可这习惯我已经该了
I talk a lot.
I've tried to break myself of the habit, but...
可你这张脸很诚实
But you have
such an honest face.
- 是吗？  - 我可以信任你，是吗？
- I have?  - I can trust you, can't I?
- 这倒是可以  - 太好了，跟我来
- Yes, I suppose so.  - Good. Come with me.
可船长那张脸也是诚实的
你干吗不去找他诉苦？
The captain has an honest face too.
Why can't you tell him your troubles?
- 去我的客舱还是你的？  - 我的
- Shall we go to your cabin or to mine?  - Ah, no, mine.
- 我的就在…  - 我的在这儿
- But mine is just around the...  - Mine is here.
不是我谨小慎微…
It's not that
I'm prudish...
是我妈妈告戒我
千万不要单独进一个男人的房间
but my mother told me never to enter
a man's room in months ending in "R."
是吗？
She did?
哎，哦，这么说你母亲不仅漂亮，而且聪明
Ah. Oh, well, your mother's
not only beautiful, she's clever too.
- 你叫什么？  - 特瑞·麦凯
- What is your name?  - Terry McKay.
特瑞·麦凯，独自一个人旅行
Terry McKay,
and I'm traveling alone.
- 是不是这事在烦呢？  - 是的
- Was that, by any chance,
what was troubling you?  - Yes.
- 可以吗？  - 可以
- May I?  - You may.
谢谢
Thank you.
呃…放在这儿就行了
Um... I think you can leave it here.
噢 这事太巧了，你救了我一命
You know, this couldn't be nicer.
You saved my life.
我都快烦死了
起程以后我在船上一个漂亮女人都没有看见
I was bored. I hadn't seen one
attractive woman on this ship since we left.
我都惊呆了
Now, isn't that terrible?
I was alarmed.
我不停地自问
“漂亮女人都不出门儿了？”
I said to myself,
"Don't beautiful women travel anymore?"
后来看见了你，但愿我这一下得救了
And then I saw you,
and I was saved, I hope.
告诉我，你是不是靠这套言辞赢得女人的？
Tell me, have you been getting results
with a line like that?
- 我一点儿也不感到惊奇？  - 你要是惊奇倒会令我惊奇
- Or would I be surprised?  - If you were surprised, I'd be surprised.
你可真会挖苦人
这种话我也能说一大堆
That sounds like a nasty crack.
I can make a few, too, if...
- 我相信你能  - 我当然能
- I'm sure you could.  - I know I can.
- 我已经说了  - 我也会说
- That's what I said.  - All right. I think I will.
- 我洗耳恭听  - 你未婚妻认识
那个加布里埃尔号的女主角？
- I'm listening.  - Does your fiancee know
the lady of the yacht, Gabriella?
当然知道，她们俩是好朋友
Why, certainly.
She's her best friend.
要好的朋友
Chummy little group.
我觉得这船走得太快了
You know, this ship is going much too fast.
每一分钟都不能白白地浪费
We ought to take advantage
of every moment.
你，你不觉得生活应该欢快灿烂…
Uh, don't you think that life
should be gay and bright...
就像冒泡的香槟吗？
and bubbly
like champagne?
- 我喜欢粉色香槟  - 我就是那个意思…
- I like pink champagne.  - That's the kind I mean... pink champagne.
我们为什么不让这次旅途
像粉色香槟那么美好？
Is there any reason why from now on
this trip shouldn't be pink champagne?
- 嗯哼  - 怎么？
- Mm-hmm.  - What?
噢，天啦
Oh, dear.
- 他不赞成？  - 不
- He wouldn't like it, hmm?  - No.
- 丈夫？  - 不是
- Husband?  - No.
- 那他也不赞成？  - 不赞成
- He still wouldn't like it?  - No.
那么 他为什么不和你一起来呢？
Uh, why isn't he
traveling with you?
- 他得去德克萨斯办理公司合并的事 - 哦
- Because he had to go to Texas on a big merger.  - Ah.
他建议在他去办那项生意期间
我最好来趟旅行…
He thought it'd be a good idea if I took
a little trip while he consummated this deal...
因为我对做生意一窍不通
because I have
no head for business.
我真是弄不明白 一个出现赤字的公司…
It's beyond me how the more money
a corporation loses...
怎样才能做到亏损越多
赚钱也越多
the more money it makes,
because of the carryovers with the write-offs.
你觉得就是让实力雄厚的大公司
去吞并弱小的小公司…
The big secret seems to be to merge a sick
corporation with a big, fat, healthy one...
这样就都好起来了
and then everybody gets well.
- 不太好吧？  - 在这类事情上…
- Silly, isn't it?  - He doesn't think I'm dumb...
他倒不认为我太笨
也不觉得我太聪明
but, um, he doesn't think
I'm very bright about things like that.
你本来就很聪明
Well, it isn't necessary, is it?
- 谢谢  - 没什么
- Thank you.  - That's all right.
- 这么说他很信任你了？  - 绝对信任
- Well... So he trusts you?  - Implicitly.
嗯 没有过失、没有差错、没有闹过小误会…
Mm, no mistakes, no errors,
no tiny little slips...
- 绝对忠实的五年  - 哦
- Five faithful years.  - Ah.
难以置信吧，可这是真的
Sounds awful,
doesn't it, but it's true.
是吗，原来是这样
Yes. Well, there you are.
- 抽吗？  - 不，谢谢
- Cigarette?  - No, thank you.
呃，我怎么没带…
Oh, I don't...
那段烫耳的赠言足以能够点着？
You could light it
from that inscription, couldn't you?
哦，说得妙，你说什么我都听着
Oh, I like...
I must stay tuned into you.
是啊，哦，他…他可真走运
一定是个出色的男子汉
Yes. Oh, he... he's a very lucky fellow.
Must be a remarkable man.
当然啦
像你这样迷人的男子我都能抵御…
Well, you can imagine
how attractive he is...
可见他的魅力有多大了…
when I can resist
so charming a person as, um...
是啊，哦，我懂了 我们交谈得很愉快？
Yes. Yes. Oh, I understand.
Well, it was nice, wasn't it?
知道吗？
Oh, well.
甲板上能玩网球、智木盘，和拼纸牌
Well, there's still deck tennis,
shuffleboard, bingo.
哦 是不是让您觉得尴尬了
Well, don't tell me
you're embarrassed.
是的，坦率地说很尴尬
Yes. Yes, as a matter
of fact, I am.
- 噢，真对不起  - 这没什么，用不着道歉
- Oh, I am sorry.  - It's all right. Don't apologize.
- 但愿这事不会伤了你的自尊…
- 哪儿能呢，想到哪儿去了，别这样想
- I do hope it won't affect your ego because...  - Don't think anything of it.
我带上我的自尊去散散步
I'll just take
my ego for a walk.
- 当然，除非你愿意…  - 和你共进晚餐？
- Unless, of course, you'd care to...  - Have dinner with you?
我当然愿意
I'd love to.
啊 我的朋友弗伦迪先生来了
Here comes my friend
Ferrante now.
啊 弗伦迪先生
这是我妹妹哈瑟维小姐…
Mr. Ferrante, I'd like to have you meet
my sister, Miss Hathaway...
我妻子哈瑟维太太…
and my wife,
Mrs. Hathaway...
那么，呃，告诉我，你小的时候…
And, uh,
when you were little...
保姆在睡觉前给你念什么书？
what did your nurse
read to you at bedtime?
- 让我想想…  - 是《卡萨诺瓦回忆录》吗？
- Let me see...  - The memoirs of Casanova?
每晚都念，然后我们就熄灯睡觉
Every night.
And then we'd turn out the light.
- “我们”？  - 那时我才这么点儿
- "We"?  - I was only so big.
- 你的童年一定非常快乐吧  - 哦，是这样
- You must've had a happy childhood.  - Ah, yes.
- 还有女人？  - 噢，女人
- And women?  - Oh, women.
- 你认识的多极了，对吗？  - 哦，说不好
- You've known quite a few, haven't you?  - Oh, I don't know.
- 是不是“极”字用错了  - 是有点儿不太确切
- Or perhaps "few" is the wrong word.  - Let's say it's not precise.
打搅您了，弗伦迪先生
I beg your pardon,
signor Ferrante.
这张桌子要不要每晚给您留着？
Would you like me to reserve this table
for you every night?
- 干吗不呢？  - 谢谢
- Why not?  - Thank you.
- 刚才说哪儿了？  - 那些女人全都发疯似地爱上了您
- Now, where were we?  - And I suppose they've all
been madly in love with you.
- 不一定  - 而您，对他们却不够尊重
- I doubt it.  - But, uh, you haven't had
much respect for them.
- 噢，恰恰相反…  - 不过您对他们的评介却很公平
- Oh, on the contrary...
- Still, you've always been very fair in your judgments.
是的，最公平不过了
Yes. I've been more than fair.
I idealize them.
我把他们视为偶像
放在至高无上的位置
Every woman I meet,
I put up there.
可认识时间一长，了解一深就…
Of course, the longer I know her
and the better I know her...
- 很难保住她们是不是？  - 是啊
- It's hard to keep them up there, isn't it?  - Yes.
很快偶像就摇晃了…
Pretty soon,
the pedestal wobbles...
没多久就倒塌了
and then topples.
现实中就是这样
C'est la vie, et cetera.
不说了，来谈谈你
Come on.
Let's talk about you.
不，今晚不行
No. Not tonight.
我的故事改天再讲
We'll talk about me
some other time.
- 明天我正好没什么安排  - 噢，可我有
- We've nothing planned for tomorrow.  - Oh, I have.
噢，那不行
Oh, no.
明天就谈我，说定了
We'll talk about me tomorrow.
噢 天气真是好极了
It turned out
beautifully, didn't it?
我都热了，谢谢
It's really warm.
Thank you.
刚才说哪儿了？
你要告诉我你的出生地
Now, where were we? You were
going to tell me where you were born.
- 就是这儿，那好…  - 弗伦迪先生？
- That's right. Well...  - Mr. Ferrante?
- 您的电报  - 谢谢
- Cablegram.  - Thank you.
请原谅，麦凯小姐
Excuse me, Miss McKay.
- 麦凯小姐？  - 对，是我
- Miss McKay?  - Yes?
- 也有您的一封  - 哦
- I have one for you too.  - Oh.
- 谢谢  - 不客气
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
请原谅，弗伦迪先生
Excuse me, Mr. Ferrante.
- 他来的？  - 她来的？
- From him?  - From her?
- 嗯哼  - 嗯哼
- Mm-hmm.  - Mm-hmm.
呃，刚才说到哪儿了？
Well, uh, where were we?
哦，说到我要告诉你我的出生地点…
Well, I was about to tell you
where I was born...
我嘛，出生在波士顿
and, um, I was born
in Boston.
- 快长大吧，我都等不及了  - 你耐心一点儿
- I can hardly wait for you to grow up.  - Yes. Well, be patient.
我马上就长大
I grew up quickly.
我去了纽约
在一家夜总会唱歌…
Then I went to New York and got a job...
从晚十点到凌晨三点
singing in a nightclub
from 10:00 to 3:00 in the morning.
然后经理会纠缠我一个小时…四点钟
The manager used to chase me around
the office until about 4:00 and then...
下班回家
I went home.
- 他有没有…  - 哦，没有  - 那就好
- Did he ever, uh...  - Oh, no, no.  - is good.
后来一天晚上…他来找我
Well, then one evening...
he came along.
- 呃，就是这家伙  - 嗯哼
- Ah. This is the fellow.  - Mm-hmm.
他来对我说…
And, uh, he said, um...
“你可不属于夜总会这种地方”
"You don't belong
in a place like this."
- 真的？  - 嗯哼
- Really?  - Mm-hmm.
我就问他“是吗”？
And I said, uh, "I don't?"
啊哈，他就…
And, uh, well, then...
- 嗯？什么？  - 什么什么？
- Hmm? What?  - What what?
- 我以为你说了什么呢  - 我什么也没说
- I thought you said something.  - I didn't say anything.
但你猜对了
But you're right, you know.
他说我属于
花园大道的一间顶楼小屋…
He said I belonged
in a penthouse on Park Avenue...
每天尽情饱览东河的美景
with a breathtaking view
of the East River.
你发奋努力的理想地方
An ideal place for you
to improve yourself.
对，于是我就开始用功
Yes. So, I studied hard.
唱歌？…
Singing? And...
- 学习音乐，艺术，文学  - 嗯
- And music and art and literature.  - Hm.
为了做一个十全十美的漂亮妻子
So that one day you'd make
a perfectly charming wife.
是啊，谁都想这样
有什么不好吗？
Yes, that was the general idea.
Anything wrong with that?
- 不不不，没什么不好  - 我真是这么想的
- No, no, there's nothing wrong with it.  - That's what I thought.
所以人人都有一番经历
Well, that sort of
brings us up-to-date.
如今我的生活是一本打开的书
Now my life
is an open book.
那只是其中的一页
That's only one page.
不，是仅有的一页
Well, that's the only page.
对不起，打扰您了
I beg your pardon.
谢谢，非常感谢
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
- 不不，这可不好  - 等一等
- No, no. Bad, bad.  - Wait a minute.
- 你的相机不错啊，可以看看吗？  - 哦，当然可以
- That's a very interesting camera.
May I see that?  - Oh, yes.
还是新的？谢谢
It's new, isn't it?
Thank you.
噢，别扔，别扔啊！
Oh, please!
Please stop!
这太不幸了？
That's unfortunate, isn't it?
这未免太过分了吧
That was not
very nice.
- 你不该那么做  - 是不该
- You shouldn't have done that.  - I know.
可以一旦登出去
显然对你对我都不好
You know, it's obviously no good,
either of us being seen together.
无论对错人们都会议论
所以你我还是再见为好
Right or wrong, people will talk,
and so I guess it had better be good-bye.
- 这可太遗憾了  - 再见
- That seems a pity.  - Good-bye.
呃，怎么回事？你害怕了？
Well, what's the matter?
Are you afraid?
- 怕你？  - 对
- Of you?  - Yeah.
不是
No.
你想想我们在船上还得呆上好几天
这寂寞我怎么能受得了
We have several days to go on this voyage,
and I can't stand monotony.
晴天时你可以在甲板上长长地散步
Well, you can always
take long walks in the sunshine.
那下雨天我怎么办？
What'll I do if it rains?
不不，我们这样不好
No. No, it's no good.
- 尤其是对你自己不好吧  - 是的
- You mean, it's particularly no good for you.  - Yes.
和你在一起可是新闻…
Being seen with you
is news...
我不想让我的形象出现在报纸上
and I don't want to get
my picture in the papers.
所以，我走我的路…
So, I'll go my way...
你呢，走你自己的路
and you'll go yours.
救命！救命！
Help! Help!
噢！噢，别急，我来了…
Oh! Oh, here. Let me...
- 噢，天哪，你可真沉啊  - 怎么了？碰上麻烦了？
- Oh, my Lord, he's heavy.  - What's the matter? Are you in trouble?
是的，帮帮忙好吗，他太沉了
Yes. Give me a hand.
He's a bit heavy.
来，老第，扶好了
Come on, chum.
I've got him.
- 好了，放开手  - 把腿放下来，让他坐一会儿
- That's right. No, let go.  - Try it the other way around, Dad.
噢，谢谢，你提醒得很对
Oh, thank you.
You're a great help.
你怎么会躺在这儿呢？
Well, how'd you come
to do that?
我被夹住了
I got...
I got tangled up.
- 嗯，下不来了是吗？  - 嗯哼
- Mm-hmm. Couldn't get down, huh?  - Mm-hmm.
嚯，你可真是个人物啊
Oh, you're quite a fella.
- 你也是个人物  - 是吗？为什么？
- You're quite a fella yourself.  - Yes? Why?
船上的每一个人都在说你呢
Everybody on the ship's
talkin' about ya.
- 是吗，都说了些什么？  - 说的什么我不知道…
- No kidding? What are they saying?  - I don't know...
每次他们说的时候就把我赶出来
on account of every time they start talkin'
about ya, they make me leave the room.
我也不知道
I don't get it.
你来吧
You take over.
你可得小心点儿，不然会受伤的
You want to watch it, chum.
You might hurt yourself.
- 我像你这么大的时候就把腿摔断了  - 现在还断吗？
- When I was little like you,
I fell and broke my leg.  - How is it now?
- 好像已经好了  - 那为什么还诉苦呢？
- It's all right, I guess.  - Well, what are ya crabbing about?
我并没有诉…
I'm not cra...
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 香槟鸡尾酒  - 就来
- Champagne cocktail, please.  - Yes, sir.
- 你这儿有香烟吗？  - 吸烟室那儿卖，先生
- Have you any cigarettes?  - The smoke room steward, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 有粉色香槟吗？  - 当然有
- Have you got pink champagne?  - Of course.
来一杯
Let me try it.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好，小姐
- Good evening.  - Good evening, mademoiselle.
- 请给我来杯香槟鸡尾酒？  - 好的，小姐
- Could I have a champagne cocktail, please?  - Yes, mademoiselle.
- 有没有粉色香槟？  - 当然有
- Do you have pink champagne?  - Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好
Hello.
我把那张桌子换成单人的了
I changed my table
to a table for one.
我也是
So did I.
这多可惜啊…
Now, isn't that a shame...
昨天我们还在一起共进晚餐？
after that delightful dinner
we had together last night?
- 你会讲盖尔语吗？  - 很流利
- And do you speak Gaelic?  - Fluently.
“我们走吧”这句话怎么说？
How do you say,
"Let's get out of here"?
嗯
Hmm.
噢 这可是太巧了！
Well, well, well!
奇怪
Well.
哦，这事儿
Oh, well, well.
真有意思？
That's good, isn't it?
- 这才叫做自欺欺人呢  - 嗯？你说什么？
- This is what's known as fooling the world.  - Hmm? What did you say?
我说这才叫做自欺欺人
I said, this is what's known
as fooling the world.
我听不清楚你的话，你大声点儿
I can't hear what you said.
What are you saying?
得了，你这是想瞒谁呀？
人人都在盯着我们
Who do you think you're hiding from?
Everybody's staring at us.
- 太可怕了，我可要走了  - 不不，这可太让我伤心了
- This is awful. I'm going to leave.  - No, no. Let me.
不要走，我马上就…
Don't worry. That made it worse.
快坐下，快坐下
Sit down! Sit down!
你忘了…
You forgot...
- 对不起，先生，这是那位小姐的  - 知道，我是想…
- Pardon me, sir. That's the lady's purse.  - Yes. I was just...
哎，等等，那是我的…
No, no. Wait a minute.
The last one...
噢
Oh!
什么…
What...
噢！噢，天哪，游泳池太小了是吗？
Oh! Oh, my, it's
a small pool, isn't it?
- 别打岔好不好，你拿走了我的香烟盒  - 不过这会儿不在手上
- Now, don't change the subject. You've got my cigarette case.
- Well, not on me.
船要在这儿停五个小时
这是弗兰契别墅
We've got a five-hour stopover here.
We're coming into Villefranche.
- 你要上岸吗？  - 是的，去拜访一位女士
- You going ashore?  - Yes. I'm calling on a lady.
哦，一站一个？
Ah. In every port, huh?
这女士是我的外婆
This happens to be
my grandmother.
- 怎么你不相信？  - 嗯，不信
- Well, don't you believe me?  - Mmm, no.
- 你愿意见见她吗？  - 可以，我很想见见你的外婆
- Would you like to meet her?  - Yes, I'd like to meet your grandmother.
那咱们就说定了
Well, you've got a date.
- 没想到吧？  - 有点儿
- Surprised?  - All right.
- 这就是给你那位外婆的礼物？  - 是的
- Is this a present for
your little old grandmother?  - Yes. Yes, it is.
- 下面可真美  - 啊？
- Isn't it beautiful down there?  - Huh?
- 我说下面可真美  - 是的
- I said, isn't it beautiful down there?  - Yes.
- 想不想听句古老的笑话？  - 说吧
- But do you want to hear an old joke?  - What?
- 如果下边景色那么美，那么为什么…  - 带我到上边？
- If it's so beautiful down there, why did...  - You bring me up here?
不过是句笑话
That's an old joke, all right.
你的那位外婆真的不是个笑话吗？
You're quite sure your grandmother
isn't an old joke?
噢，但愿你能相信我
Oh, I do wish
you'd trust me.
噢！这地方可真幽静啊
Oh! What a divine place.
啊！简直绝了！
It's perfect!
- 我开始相信你有个外婆了  - 哦，这可是新闻
- I'm beginning to think
you have a grandmother.  - Oh, that's surprising.
我要找到她给你瞧瞧
I'll try to find her and prove it.
雁努！
Janou!
雁努？雁努？
Janou? Janou?
她不在
She's not there.
明白了
Look.
她一定是去教堂了
She must be in the chapel.
啊，菲德尔！
Ah, Fidel!
你好吗，伙计？
对，是我，你怎么样，小伙子？
How are you, fella?
Yes, yes, yes. How are you, boy?
这地方可真有特色
What is it about this place?
周围的一切让人不敢大声说话
There's something about it
that makes you want to whisper.
这里宁静极了，就像另一个世界
It's so peaceful here.
It's like another world.
的确是，这是我外婆的世界
Mm-hmm. Well, it is.
It's my grandmother's world.
讲讲你的外婆好吗
Do tell me
more about her.
我外公生前在外交界任职
My grandfather was
in the diplomatic service.
夫妇两个走遍了全世界
外公离职以后，就来这儿定居
They traveled all over the world,
and when he retired, they came here to live.
他就埋在教堂后面
He's buried there
behind the chapel.
外婆一直守在这儿
She stayed on
to be near him.
她好像等得…
等得有点儿不耐烦了…
She must be waiting...
I think a little impatiently...
想早点儿与外公相会
For the day
she would join him.
哦，尼古拉！
Oh, Nicolo!
哦！
Oh!
哦，尼古拉！
Oh, Nicolo!
你怎么不事先说一声
[French]
我想给您来个大吃一惊
- 我听说你要结婚了  - 是的，好像是的
- [French]  - [French]
您真是越来越年轻了
[Ferrante Speaking French]
哦，你来可太好了，尼古拉，太好了！
Oh, Nicolo!
- 是她吗？  - 不，不是
- [French]  - Non, non.
- 亲爱的，这位是特瑞·麦凯  - 你好啊
- Darling, this is Terry McKay.  - How do you do?
- 您好  - 外婆把你当成我的未婚妻了
- How do you do?  - Janou thought you were
the girl I'm going to marry.
- 哦！  - 真漂亮，我非常喜欢她
- Oh!  - [French]
噢，对不起，我说我非常喜欢你
Oh, pardon moi.
I was only saying I like you very much.
噢，谢谢，我很高兴
Oh, thank you. I'm glad.
请别见怪，我得坐一会儿
Well, if you will excuse me,
I must sit down.
我祈祷的时间加长了
I am longer
at my prayers nowadays.
噢，我的膝盖呀！
Oh, my knees!
一把老骨头了啰
They're as old as I am.
噢，我从没见过这么美的地方
Oh, you have
the most beautiful place here.
- 谢谢  - 我真想永远在这儿住下去
- Thank you.  - I think I could stay here forever.
噢，这可不行
你还太年轻，亲爱的
No, no, no.
You are too young for that, my dear.
这里只适合静静地回忆往事…
It is a good place
to sit and remember...
而你，你的记忆还没有填满呢
but you have still
to create your memories.
还有教堂也这么迷人
And the chapel
seems so charming.
- 噢，想进去看看吗？  - 哦，可以吗？
- Oh, would you like to go in?  - Oh, may I?
- 当然可以  - 哦，谢谢
- [French]  - Oh, thank you.
哦，尼古拉！
Oh, Nicolo!
你呢，尼古拉…
And you, Nicolo...
你有多久没有进教堂了？
how long is it since you
have been in a chapel?
- 哦，这个…  - 还是小时候进的？
- Oh, well, I...  - Not since you were an altar boy, huh?
- 是的  - 去吧，他不会伤害你
- Ah, no.  - Go in. It won't hurt you.
- 好吧  - 我去沏壶茶
- All right.  - I will prepare the tea.
- 那么我来帮您  - 不用，不用，去吧
- Let me help you.  - No, no, no, no. [French]
马瑞阿斯
Marius!
- 马瑞阿斯  - 来了，夫人
- Marius!  - Oui, madame.
- 噢，快猜猜谁来了  - 是谁来了？夫人
- [French]  - [French]
你看呐
[French]
噢！尼古拉先生！
Oh! Monsieur Nicholas!
嗨！啊！
Oh! Ah!
- 马瑞阿斯！  - 太好了！
- Marius!  - [French]
我们又见面了，我太高兴了！太高兴了！
[French]
- 又有孩子了？  - 哦，对的，跟外婆在一起，去看看吧
- [French]  - [French]
- 这是玛丽  - 喔，你好！
- This is Marie.  - Well, hello!
- 这个是最小的  - 对，她是最小的
- [French]  - [French]
- 一共几个了？  - 哦，七个 你走的时候是…呃，是三个
这是我的朋友马瑞阿斯
This is my friend Marius.
- 哦，您好，小姐  - 您好
- Oh, madame.  - Hello.
我上次见他时他才三个孩子
Marius has had three children
since I last saw him.
马瑞阿斯说法兰西缺人
Marius says
France needs men.
所以就生了七个女儿
So he has seven daughters.
- 去看看我的全家吧  - 去吧，去吧
- Come to see the rest of my family.  - Yes, go along.
- 可以吗？  - 我顺便和麦凯小姐谈谈
- Sure?  - I should like a little
tete-a-tete with Miss McKay.
哦，雁努，千万客气点儿
Oh, Janou, please be kind.
不会说你坏话
I won't betray you.
- 我来帮您吧？  - 哦，谢谢，亲爱的
- Can I help you?  - Oh, thank you, my dear.
现在的年轻人对家务一窍不通…
I am glad you are not
like so many young people nowadays...
你不这样我很高兴
Above a little housework.
我们家兄弟姐妹十个
人人都得干活…
There were ten of us in our family.
We all had to do our share...
不然就不给晚饭吃
or go to bed
without supper.
- 噢，这客厅真漂亮！  - 哦，是啊
- Oh, what a magnificent room!  - Oh, yes.
我丈夫曾经是个有名的收藏家
My husband was
a great collector.
他喜欢漂亮的东西
He loved
beautiful things.
我也是
Me too.
我请过两位管家，可都比我先死了…
I should have a housekeeper,
but I have outlived two...
我太老了，没气力再训练新的了
and I'm too old to start
breaking in another one.
再说我不想瞒你…
Besides, I... I don't
mind telling you...
我原来只想活到80岁
I had planned only
to live till I was 80.
可现在都82了
Now I am 82.
如果一时半会儿死不了
我得为自己的晚年存点儿钱才行
Well, if I'm not going to die,
I must start saving money for my old age.
您想得很对
You're very wise.
- 啊！  - 喜欢吗？
- Ah!  - You like it?
喜欢，很美
Mmm, yes.
It's charming.
谁…
Who...
- 弗伦迪？  - 尼古拉！
- Ferrante?  - Nicolo!
- 尼基？  - 是的，他很久以前画的
- Nickie?  - Yes. He did that a long time ago.
噢，他画得还真不错
Oh, but it's very good.
他很有点儿才气
He is very talented.
噢，对不起，我以前一点儿也不知道他会画画
Oh, forgive me.
You see, I had no means of knowing.
噢，令人非常惋惜的是他又非常苛刻
Oh. Unfortunately,
he is also very critical.
才气让他创作
苛刻让他销毁
The artist in him would create.
The critic would destroy.
- 到头来他这人一无所成  - 太可惜了
- As a result, he has done nothing since.  - What a pity.
嗯，再说，他一直在忙于人们所说的生活
Mm-hmm. Besides, he's been too busy...
living, as they call it.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
- 我来吧？  - 哦，谢谢，亲爱的
- May I?  - Oh, thank you, my dear.
给
There.
噢，你们到这里来看我真让我兴奋不已
Oh, it has been such
a tremendous excitement for me, this visit.
我激动得难以平静
I am trying
to appear calm.
- 你觉得我现在怎么样？  - 看起来您的气色好极了
- Don't you think I do pretty well?  - You do wonderfully well.
- 您请  - 谢谢
- Here we are.  - Thank you.
我非常喜欢尼古拉
I love Nicolo so much.
他还很小的时候…
When he was a small boy...
就弹得一手好钢琴 我们都很惊讶
he charmed us all
with his piano playing.
后来又开始画画
Then he studied painting.
最要命的就是他什么都拿得起来
And the worst of it is
he's so good at everything.
不折不扣的万事通
Ajack-of-all-talents.
什么事对他都太容易了
Everything comes
too easily to him.
他的注意力总是转向他不会的画法
He's always attracted by the art
he isn't practicing.
他没去过的地方，他不认识的女孩儿
The place he hasn't been,
the girl he hasn't met.
也许我不该和他相识
Perhaps I shouldn't
have met him.
不，亲爱的，你是个例外
No, my dear.
You are different.
我不妨对你直言不讳…
I don't mind
confessing to you...
我一直在为他担心
I have been worried
about him.
- 有时候还很害怕  - 为什么？
- Sometimes I'm frightened.  - Why?
我怕生活会赠给尼古拉一张帐单…
That life will present
a bill to Nicolo one day...
而他却无法支付
and he will find it
hard to pay.
我看见你和他在一起，我放心多了
But when I see you with him,
I feel better.
- 真的？真的放心？  - 当然是真的
- Me? You do?  - Yes. You.
但愿我也能有您这种信心
Well, I wish I could share
your confidence.
必要时你会有的
You will have it
when you need it.
这是你的性格
That is your character.
噢，一个好妻子能把尼古拉的…
Oh, there is nothing wrong
with Nicolo...
所有缺点都纠正过来的
that a good woman
couldn't make right.
嗯
Mm.
嗨，马瑞阿斯的全家我都见了，七个女儿
Well, I saw Marius's entire family.
Seven daughters.
我向他贺了喜还和他太太聊了天
I congratulated him
and had a nice talk with his wife.
你应该和他再聊一会儿
别坐了我的帽子
You should have had a nice talk with him.
And don't sit on my hat.
告诉我，你们刚才都聊了些什么？
Tell me, what have you two
been talking about?
- 嗯，是你想不到的  - 这我相信
- Hmm. Oh, you'd be surprised.  - I'll bet I would.
- 我还敢打赌都是外婆一个人在说  - 嗯哼
- And I'll bet thatJanou did all the talking.  - Mm-hmm.
外婆告诉我说你小时候很调皮
一碰上不顺心的事…
She's been telling me that when you were
a little boy and didn't get your own way...
就躺在地板上乱踢乱闹
you'd lie on the floor and kick
and get red in the face.
是吗？嗯… 那只眼怎么不挤一下？
Really? Uh... You should've winked the other eye.
- 噢！ - 你怎么说的？
- Oh!  - And what did you say?
我说你现在不调皮了
I said you didn't
do that anymore.
- 不了！  - 不了
- No!  - No.
现在碰上不顺心的事
只有自我苦恼
Now when you don't get your own way,
you just get embarrassed.
喝茶吗？
Want some tea?
这件事我不想跟您做出解释
Remind me not to explain
that to you later.
好的，我喝杯茶
Yes, I want some tea.
- 雁努，我给您带了礼物！  - 噢！尼古拉
- Janou, I have a gift for you.  - Oh! Nicolo.
- 来瞧瞧  - 还给老太婆带礼物
- Come and see it.  - I am too old for gifts.
送礼物可不分老少
No one's too old for gifts.
你真不该这么胡乱花钱
You shouldn't spend
your money so recklessly.
我没花多少，我帮您打开
It didn't cost much.
Let me help you.
哦，尼古拉
Oh, Nicolo.
你怎么画的？
How did you do it?
根据记忆画的，谢谢
I did it from memory.
Thank you.
- 哦  - 是安德烈…
- Oh.  - It is Andre...
我的丈夫
my husband.
噢，真像他…
Oh, it's so real...
太像他了
so like him.
这张脸真动人
What a remarkable face.
- 你真的是根据记忆画的？  - 是的
- Did you do that from memory?  - Yes.
喜欢吗？
Do you like it?
噢，喜欢极了
Oh, it's wonderful.
其实我早就画好了
可我当时不敢把它送给您
I painted that a long time ago,
but I hesitated about giving it to you.
我说过他很有才华
I told you he has talent.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
- 请，给你的  - 给我的？谢谢
- Well, now, for you.  - For me? Thank you.
给您
For you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的
For me.
- 每人一杯  - 我想说几句祝酒词
- Well, now.  - I should like to propose a little toast.
可不知怎么说才好
Uh... I don't quite know
how to phrase it.
您是不是想祝贺他…
Well, uh, would it
have something to do...
婚姻美满幸福快乐？
with his
happy marriage?
嗯，我…
Mm, I...
这么说吧…
Shall we say...
祝你们二位的归途顺利愉快
may your voyage home
be a pleasant one.
谢谢
Thank you.
不早了，我们得回船上去了
Well, now, I'm afraid
we must be leaving soon.
今天过得真快活
It has been a good day.
我们走之前
您给我们弹段钢琴好吗？
Now, before we go,
you must play the piano for us.
- 噢，不行，尼古拉  - 来吧
- Oh, no, Nicolo.  - Come along.
- 不行，多年没弹了  - 弹一段吧
- No, no, no.  - Please do.
- 瞧我这双手  - 没关系，弹吧，弹吧
- Look at my hands.  - No excuses. Come along.
弹吧
Come on.
噢
Ohh.
外婆是个专业钢琴家
Janou was a concert pianist.
过去是
Was.
别忘了是你们强迫我弹的
Remember, I was asked
to do this.
我真恨开船的汽笛声
I don't like boat whistles.
亲爱的，外面有风，您披上这个吧？
Don't you think you should put this
around your shoulders?
谢谢，亲爱的
Thank you, my dear.
- 披肩真漂亮！  - 喜欢吗？
- It's lovely, isn't it?  - You like it?
非常喜欢
Yes, I do.
- 将来我会送给你的  - 噢，这哪行啊
- One day, I will send it to you.  - Oh, no.
我很愿意送给你
I would like to.
我就送到这儿了
This is as far as I go.
这儿是我居住的小世界的边界
This is the boundary
of my small world.
嗯
Hmm.
啊！一个理想的世界
Oh! It's a perfect world.
谢谢您让我闯了进来
Thank you for
letting me trespass.
再见
Good-bye.
保佑你
Bless you.
那好，再见了，亲爱的外婆
Well, au revoir, dearJanou.
我会很快再来看您
我会经常写信的
I'll come back to see you very soon,
and I'll write often.
- 一定写  - 一定写
- Please do.  - I will.
噢！祝您愉快，亲爱的
Oh! Happy thoughts, darling.
再见，我的孩子
Adieu, mon petit.
噢
Oh.
再见
Good-bye.
我到处在找你
I've been looking
everywhere for you.
还打了电话给你…
I called your cabin...
你哭过了
You've been crying.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
是美景把我感动了
Beauty does that to me.
尼基，谢谢你带我度过了…
Nickie, I... I want
to thank you for the...
我一生当中最快活最难忘的一天
The loveliest and the most memorable day
I've ever known.
你对我外婆真是太好了
You were very sweet
to my little grandmother.
我准备给她写信
I'm going to write to her.
那太好了
That'll be nice.
散散步吧，嗯？
Let's walk, hmm?
怎么又哭了
No more tears.
我说了我是被美景感动了
I told you that's what beauty does to me.
船已驶向大海了，尼基
We're heading into
a rough sea, Nickie.
知道，我们今天改变了航向
I know. We changed
our course today.
- 嗯  - 送你回卧舱好吗？
- Mm-hmm.  - Shall I see you to your cabin?
不必送
I don't think so.
晚安
Good night.
请等一下
Just a moment.
- 特瑞…  - 噢！你怎么敢来这儿？
- Terry...  - Oh! Why did you come here?
- 你知道这很危险  - 亲爱的，我们得好好谈谈
- You know it's dangerous.  - Darling, we got a lot to talk about.
是该谈谈，可让别人看见
你知道，对我们两个人都没好处
I am aware of that, but to be seen together
could be disastrous for us both.
可是我们得商量一下
有个问题急需要解决
I know, but we have some fast thinking to do.
We've created a problem.
这我知道
Yes, I know.
那么就别让问题复杂化了
So let's not
complicate it any more.
作为女人我生来就比你谨慎…
Being a woman,
I'm naturally more cautious...
你不在，我的头脑会更清晰一些
and I can think more clearly
when you're not around.
所以你回屋想你的
我就在这儿想我的
So you go think in your room,
and I'll think in mine.
- 好吧  - 在思考中彼此想念
- All right.  - While we miss each other.
噢，这话说得好，说得太好了
Oh, that was very sweet,
what you just said.
- 早上好，先生  - 早上好，小姐
- [Irish Accent] Top of the mornin' to you.  - And the rest of the day to you.
- 听我说  - 不，不行
- No, listen. What?  - No, no.
- 你快走你的  - 哦，真倒霉
- Keep moving.  - Oh, dear.
等等，先别走
Wait a minute.
Don't go away.
- 你考虑出什么结果了没有？  - 没有，你快走吧
- Now, have you come to any conclusions yet?  - No. Keep moving.
哦，糟糕
Oh, dear.
- 我想你  - 我也想你
- I miss you.  - I miss you too.
- 那就多给我打电话？  - 我试试吧，不过你知道
- Why don't you telephone more often?  - I'll try, but you know.
- 你有话要说吗？  - 没有，我没什么要说的
- Were you going to say something?  - I wasn't going to say anything.
听着，一起吃顿饭总可以吧…
Listen. Couldn't we
at least eat together...
在你的房间或我的房间？
in your room or my room?
不行，不等我们吃上色拉
就会被传得满船风雨
The news would be all around the ship
before we'd had our salad.
船员也会说三道四的
你快朝那边转吧，我头都晕了
The crew talks too. Do go around
the other way. You're making me dizzy.
可以，这样对我也有好处
Be better for me also,
I can tell you that.
哦，等一等，亲爱的…
Oh, wait a minute.
Darling. Uh...
听着，亲爱的，我…
Listen, darling, I...
真奇怪
That's odd.
你好
Well.
- 晚上好，先生  - 晚上好，麦凯小姐在吗？
- Good evening, sir.  - Good evening. Is Miss McKay dining?
在，要去找她吗？
Yes, sir.
Would you care to join her?
- 她可能喜欢一个人用餐  - 她马上就用完
- I think she prefers to dine alone.  - She's almost finished, sir.
哇，嗯…
Whew. Mm, mm.
点浓味鱼肉汤，味道好极了
Order the bouillabaisse.
It's superb.
- 非常感谢  - 没什么
- [French]  - [French]
哦，住嘴
Oh, shut up.
请进
Come in.
- 你好啊  - 哦，你好啊，哈瑟维先生
- Hello there.  - Oh, hello, Mr. Hathaway.
麦凯小姐，弗伦迪在哪儿？
Miss McKay, uh...
where's Ferrante?
弗伦… 噢，我怎么知道？
Ferra... Well,
how should I know?
噢，别装了，有人告诉我他在您这儿
Oh, come now. A little bird told me
he might be in here.
噢，哈瑟维先生
你不觉得你这样有点儿太无礼了吗？
Oh, really, Mr. Hathaway.
Don't you think you're being
a little rude and presumptuous?
- 我根本没看见弗伦迪先生…  - 你好，特瑞
- I haven't seen Mr. Ferrante since...  - Hello, Terry.
噢 呵
Oh ho!
- 我想你可能喜欢这本书  - 我看过了
- It occurred to me you might like this book.  - Yeah. I've read it.
好几天没看见你了
我还以为你已经下船了呢
I haven't seen you for days.
I thought you must have got off somewhere.
哪儿能呢，这船还没到站呢！
Why, no. We haven't docked anywhere.
也许再也见不着了吧
麦凯小姐，祝你愉快
Well, in case I don't see you again,
Miss McKay, uh, happy landing.
谢谢，弗伦迪先生
你别说得这么绝对，也许…
Thank you, Mr. Ferrante,
and don't think it hasn't been absolute...
噢 请您先别走
我想请二位帮个忙可以吗？
Now, slow down. I'm wondering
if you two would do me a big favor.
- 什么事？  - 能否请你在这照片上签个名字？
- What's that?  - Would you be so kind as to autograph these?
我太太，我妹妹和我每人买了一张
My wife and my sister and I
each bought a different one.
- 你们买的？  - 哪儿买的？
- You bought them?  - From whom?
从船上的摄影师那儿
他在上层甲板上摆了一大排
The ship's photographer.
He has a big display up on the promenade deck.
正在那儿大力推销呢！
He's doing a wholesale business.
这样吧，哈瑟维先生，我们先商量一下
我到哪儿去找你？
Well, we'll have to think about it.
Now, where could I find you?
我嘛，如果不在酒吧的话…
Well, I'll either be
in the cocktail lounge...
当然就在餐厅里了
or, of course, the dining room.
那好吧
Yes, of course.
- 瞧瞧！  - 噢！
- Well.  - Oh!
- 我倒不在乎这张，蛮不错的  - 噢，别开玩笑了！
- I don't mind that one. That's pretty good.  - Oh, do be serious!
这太可怕了！
This is dreadful!
- 我们想尽了办法 还以为瞒住他们呢  - 是啊
- And after all the pains
we took deceiving everybody.  - Yes.
我尤其为你感到遗憾
I'm particularly sorry for you.
不过我并不像我预料的那么遗憾
You know, I'm not as sorry
as I thought I'd be.
像逃犯一样
躲来躲去太傻了，不是吗？
It was rather silly,
hiding like fugitives, wasn't it?
是的，是的，是这样
Yes. Yes, I know.
那么就把这作为新的开端
去抛头露面怎么样？
So, to coin a new cliche,
shall we join the others?
那好吧，干吗不去？
有什么可顾虑的？
Well, all right. Well, why not?
What have we got to lose?
- 最后一晚了应该尽情享受  - 对呀
- The last night. Let's make the most of it.  - Good.
嗨，哈瑟维
Hi, Hathaway.
嘿！再帮个忙吧，咱们换换舞伴
Hey! Do me another favor.
Let's swap partners.
- 最后一晚上人人都换  - 那太好了
- It's the last night out. Everybody does it.  - They do? How nice.
既然这样，我们就来个例外
In your case,
we'll make an exception.
那家伙真怪
I don't get that guy.
♪ 一天又一天 我们久别胜新婚 ♪
# Day by day I'm growing fonder #
♪ 你对我的温柔 ♪
# Of those tender things you do #
噢，跳得真好
Oh, nice crossing.
你们好
Hello.
- 出去透透气吧  - 我们去看船舵
- Let's get some air.  - Yeah. Come on. I'll show you the rudder.
- 在哪儿？  - 船尾
- Where is it?  - Aft.
- 带上外套  - 小心点儿
- Got to get my coat. - Careful.
♪ 想些坏心眼的事 ♪
# Can't you think of something spiteful #
♪ 故意为难你去做 ♪
# Something mean that you could do #
- ♪ 想必你非常高兴 ♪   - 嗯
- # Must you be so darn delightful #  - Mm-hmm.
♪ 因为一切都成真 ♪
# You make it easy to be true #
要是永远这样该多好啊？
Why can't we go on
doing this forever, hmm?
我跟船长要求过了，他说不行
I had a talk with the captain.
It won't work. No.
船长说他不能掉转船头
He said he can't turn the ship around.
他本人倒是没意见
他说别人都想回家
Quite nice about it, but he said
that most of the people want to get home.
- 真可气？  - 嗯哼
- Isn't that silly?  - Mm-hmm.
我能理解船长的难处…总不能只带我们两个人
Well, I can understand his problem...
Cruising around in the ocean...
在海上转悠吧
with just the two of us.
♪ 因为一切都成真 ♪
# You make it easy to be true ##
别问我在想什么
不然我就跳海里去
If you say, "a penny for your thoughts,"
I'll jump overboard.
快到了…
Well...
明天上午，纽约
tomorrow morning, New York.
是啊
Yes.
他来接你？
Will he be waiting?
她呢？
Will she?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
噢，是的
Oh, yes.
是什么老给生活出难题？
What makes life so difficult?
人吗？
People?
你爱他吗？
Are you in love with him?
现在不爱了
I'm not now.
嗯
Mmm.
要知道，我到现在
还从来没正经干过工作
You know, I've never done
a day's work in my whole life.
- 我从来没有…  - 我知道，我一直在考虑这点
- In my whole life, I've never...  - I know. I've been thinking about that.
- 你说什么？  - 我什么也没说
- Mmm? What'd you say?  - I didn't say anything.
- 不对，你说了  - 什么？
- Yes, yes, you did.  - What?
嗯，你说我就喜欢那些华贵的东西
Hmm. You said I was very fond
of expensive things.
皮大衣、钻石呀那一类玩意
Furs and diamonds
and stuff like that.
- 是我说的吗？  - 嗯 粉色香槟
- Did I say that?  - Mm-hmm. Pink champagne.
咱们两个人已经习惯了这种饮料
That's the kind of life
we've both been used to.
改喝别的恐怕难以…
It might be
a little difficult to...
- 喜欢啤酒吗？  - 嗯，口味不同
- Do you like beer?  - Mmm, mmm, different.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
我父亲就喝啤酒，早上喝
My father drank beer
in the morning.
- 是不是很能喝？  - 是的
- He was a beer drinker?  - Mm-hmm.
嗯
Hmm.
到了后来他什么都喝
Later in the day,
he drank anything.
噢，失去温馨记忆的人，冬天一定倍觉寒冷
Oh, winter must be cold for those
with no warm memories.
一定更加想念春天
We've already
missed the spring.
是啊，这可能是我最后一次机会
Yes. Well, this is
probably my last chance.
我也一样
Mine too.
抓不住就完了
It's now or never.
噢，“完了”这词儿太可怕了
Oh, "never" is
a frightening word.
把幸福放跑那才是地道的傻瓜
We'd be fools to let
happiness pass us by.
- 嗯嗯，还有因为你没有… - 工作…
- Mm-hmm. And just because you haven't... - Work.
这不等于我没有能力
I haven't worked
doesn't mean to say I couldn't, hmm?
当然对
No, of course not.
如果我…
Suppose, I, uh...
要知道这需要时间…
给我半年怎么样…如果…
It would take some time...
say, six months... to find out if, uh...
- 如果？如果什么？  - 我在假设
- lf? If what?  - Well, just suppose.
- 还是来点儿真的好  - 好吧
- Now, be realistic.  - All right.
如果我拼命地干上它一段时间
比如说六个月…
If I worked hard enough and long enough,
say, for, uh, six months...
你那会儿在哪儿？
where would you be?
你到底在想说什么，尼基？
What are you trying
to say, Nickie?
我…我是想具备…具备向你求婚的资格
Well, I... I just want to be worthy
of asking you to marry me.
噢，尼基，没有比这话更动人的了…
Oh, Nickie, that's
just about the nicest...
你的嗓子哑了
Your voice cracked.
- 噢，这是因为我…  - 别说了，我知道
- Oh, well, that's because I...  - Yes, I know. I know.
我马上就去上床…
I'm going to turn in now...
我要好好去掂量掂量、琢磨琢磨…
and do some more
rolling and tossing...
考虑考虑
and thinking about it.
明早给你回答好吗？嗯？
Let me tell you
in the morning, hmm?
这漫漫长夜够难熬的
It's going
to be a long night.
嗯，我也一样
Mm-hmm. For me too.
你知道结婚对我来说
是件非常严肃的大事
Marriage is a very serious step
for a girl like me.
这我知道
Yes, I know.
- 你喜欢孩子吗？  - 当然，非常喜欢
- Do you like children?  - Yes. Yes, I do.
- 尼基  - 噢，我担心极了
- Nickie.  - Oh, I was so worried.
我连外套都没来得及穿
I didn't even have time
to get dressed.
凌晨五点我才睡着
I didn't get
to sleep until 5:00.
- 我根本就没睡  - 哦
- I didn't sleep at all.  - Oh.
- 好，你仔细听着  - 说吧
- Now, listen carefully.  - Yes.
如果一切顺利的话
我是指你我两个人六个月以后…
If everything goes right,
and I mean for both of us, in six months...
- 给，我都写在这纸上了  - 现在能看吗？
- Here. I started to write it out.  - Should I read it now?
- 嗯哼  - 好吧
- Mm-hmm.  - All right.
- 亲爱的，是指我？  - 嗯
- "Darling..." that's me?  - Mm-hmm.
我答应与你相见
七月一号下午五点
"You have a date, my beloved,
July 1 at 5:00."
- 怎么没写地址  - 地点随你 哪儿都行
- But you don't say where.  - You name the place, and I'll obey.
定哪儿呢，脑子都乱了
I don't know.
I can't think.
帝国大厦顶层你看怎么样？
How about the top of
the Empire State Building?
噢，太好了，再合适不过了
Oh, yes, that's perfect.
- 那是纽约离上帝最近的地方  - 那好
- It's the nearest thing to heave we have in New York.  - Well.
第102层，别忘了乘电梯
The 102nd floor,
and don't forget to take the elevator.
我才不乘呢
No, I won't.
亲爱的，万一事情不顺利…
Darling, if things
don't work out...
别这样说，我不要听
Don't talk like that.
I'm not listening.
- 万一有一方不能赴约…  - 我们都会去的
- But just in case one of us is...  - We'll both be there.
- 一定要坚信  - 我坚信
- Hold the thought.  - Hold the thought.
- 多保重  - 多保重
- Take care.  - Take care.
嗯
Hmm.
- 噢！尼基，亲爱的！  - 你好
- Oh! Nickie darling!  - Hello!
- 你能来我太高兴了  - 哦，尼基  - 你好吗？
- Well, I'm so glad to see you.  - Oh, Nickie.  - How've you been?
见到你真是太高兴了
旅途顺利吗？
I'm so glad to see you.
Did you have a good trip?
还不错，不过就是有些颠簸，不过还是很愉快
Not too bad.
A little rough in spots, but very pleasant.
请别动照张相
好极了，谢谢
Hold it for a picture.
That's fine. Thank you.
- 看见皮基先生了吗？  - 我也来照一张？
- Did you get to see Pinky?  - May I have one, too, please?
- 可以，这样行吗？  - 谢谢
- Yes, how's this?  - Thank you.
- 没有，可能是去了丹吉尔  - 我可以再照一张吗？
- No, I think he's on his way to Tangiers.  - May I have another one?
他总是东跑西颠的，可以
He's always going off
someplace. Yes.
- 太好了，谢谢  - 再来一张
- That's fine. Thank you.  - Another one, please.
哦，对不起，我有点儿要紧事先过去一下
Oh, excuse me.
I have an important appointment.
- 对不起，非常抱歉  - 可以吗？
- Excuse me. Thank you so much.  - May I?
- 特瑞，亲爱的  - 你好，亲爱的，好久没见了
- Terry darling.  - Hello, darling. It's been so long.
太好了，你终于回来了
It's wonderful
to have you back.
回来真好
It's wonderful
to be back, Ken.
亲爱的，车在那儿
Darling, the car's around here.
- 怎么啦？我们走吧？  - 对对，走吧
- What's the matter? Shall we get going?  - Yes, thanks. Shall we?
- 车就停在这儿  - 太好了
- The car's right out here.  - Good.
亲爱的，有件事我得跟你商量一下
Darling, there's something
I must discuss with you.
咱们在这儿安安静静地单独聊聊…
It's been on my mind, so let's go in here
where we can be alone and quiet...
他们在这儿干什么？
What in the world
is all this?
- 我没告诉你吗？  - 没有
- Didn't I mention it?  - What?
电视台记者一直追着要采访我…
Dear, the TV people have been after me
for an interview, so I finally said yes...
我的条件是给我的慈善机构捐笔款子
他们果真捐了
if they give a big donation
to my favorite charity, and they did.
你不介意吧，亲爱的？
这是件好事
You don't mind, do you, darling?
It's for a good cause.
- 倒也是 但该事先告诉我一声  - 哦，听我说，我知道
- I wish you'd let me know.  - Oh, listen, I know you.
如果事先告诉你
你准会不肯下船了
If I'd told you,
I'd never have got you off the ship.
一号机负责近距离拍摄
Camera one,
take close-ups.
亲爱的，这是刘易斯先生
就是他要采访我们
Nickie, dear, this is Mr. Lewis
who's going to interview us.
- 富尔顿·刘易斯先生  - 啊，是罗伯特
- Mr. Fulton Q. Lewis.  - Uh, Robert.
罗伯特·富尔顿，您好
Robert Fulton,
how do you do?
不，是罗伯特·刘易斯
人们经常弄错
No, Robert Q. Lewis,
but everybody does that.
这样吧，您来晚了，弗伦迪先生
You're a little late, and we've got to go on the air.
- 转播马上就要开始了，我们现在开始吧？  - 好的
- Would you mind coming over
here, Miss Clarke, please?  - Yes.
你们到这边来坐好不好
Sit yourselves right down here.
好，你们就坐在这个位置，我就问几个问题…
I'm going to ask a few questions,
then we're going to...
他的面部怎么样？
太亮了？那好，哈里
What about his face?
Shiny. Look, uh, Harry.
擦一下脸？
哈里，动做要快一点儿
Would you mind a little makeup?
Harry, just blot it.
- 对不起，亲爱的，一会儿就好  - 但愿
- I'm sorry, darling. It'll be over with soon.  - I hope so.
那件…那件白衬衫…
反差太大？好的
Incidentally, that white shirt...
How about that? Glares.
- 您有没有蓝色的衬衫？  - 没有，没带
- You don't happen to have a blue shirt?  - No, not with me.
哦，好的，没关系，我们有办法
Ah, well, yes.
Well, look, don't worry. We'll manage.
现在我来解释一下我的打算
我想问二位几个问题…
Let me explain what I'm going to do.
I'd like to ask a few questions about how you met...
- 就几个  - 好吧
- Just a few.  - I will.
你们是怎么认识
您有什么打算等等问题
Just how you met, what your plans are
and things like that.
- 放松点儿，不必紧张  - 谢谢
- You make yourselves comfortable.  - Thank you.
- 还有五秒钟，刘易斯先生  - 知道了
- Five seconds, Mr. Lewis.  - Right.
还有眼睛就是要看着镜头
那个红灯一亮就表示开始
One thing, watch the camera.
When the red light is on, you're on.
瞧，已经亮了
Yeah? Well, it's on.
噢，观众们好
欢迎您收看本集《千家万户》节目…
Oh, hello there, and welcome to another
House to House program...
本节目由本顿婴儿公司提供赞助
brought to you by
the Benton Baby Food Company.
别忘了，本顿食品 育儿佳品
Remember, Benton's
builds better babies.
今天我们的摄像机
架在了洛伊斯·克拉克小姐的府上…
Today, our cameras are placed
in the home of Miss Lois Clarke...
她是美国最富有的女继承人之一
heiress to one of
America's greatest fortunes.
一会儿我们将见到克拉克小姐…
In just a moment,
we'll meet Miss Clarke...
和她未婚夫尼基·弗伦迪先生…
and her fiance,
Mr. Nickie Ferrante...
我请他们谈谈
他们真实动人的罗曼史…
and talk to them about their
wonderful true-to-life romance...
他们的爱情故事
已经登在了全国各大报纸的头版头条…
which has gotten headlines
in papers all over the country...
引起了世界各国的瞩目
a romance which has captured
the imagination of the whole world.
但首先请看本顿广告…
But first...
您觉得他俩相爱吗？
Do you think they're in love?
- 我怎么知道，格拉迪斯  - 我一直盼着见见尼基·弗伦迪
- I wouldn't know, Gladys.  - I can't wait to see that Nickie Ferrante.
虽然我不知道采访人会问什么…
I don't know what the
$64 million question was...
但他肯定知道该怎么回答
but he's certainly
got the answer.
倒霉
Point killer.
特瑞，亲爱的
Terry, darling.
嗯哼
Hmph.
呆会儿我要问问 你的吻怎么不那么温柔了
Remind me to ask you later
why your kisses don't seem quite the same.
但愿是因为离别得太久了
Maybe you're just
out of practice, I hope.
干吗非得看这破玩意儿？
We don't need
that darn thing on, do we?
哦，你还没有换衣服
Oh, I see you
haven't changed yet.
我给你的时间
足够换件更漂亮的衣服…
I thought I gave you plenty of time
to get into something more...
是这样，肯，我们要谈的事太多了…
Well, Ken, we have
so much to talk about...
再说我觉得这件衣服挺不错的
and I can just think better
in this outfit.
不，亲爱的
我以为旅行会对你有益处
You know, darling,
I hoped the trip would be good for you.
可是你的气色不很好
But I'm afraid
you don't look so well.
怎么回事？
是不是太颠簸了？
What's the matter?
Was it a rough crossing?
是的，是的，是有点儿颠簸
Yes... Yes.
Yes, it was a little.
哦
Oh.
我说，肯，节目肯定很有趣
You know, Ken, that program
might have been amusing.
洛伊斯·克拉克和
尼基·弗伦迪马上就要出来了
Lois Clarke and Nickie Ferrante
were about to come on.
我只对你感兴趣
如果你觉得好看…
I'm only interested in you, dear,
but if it'll entertain you...
- 嗯哼，会好看的  - 那好吧
- Mm-hmm. Yes, it will.  - Okay.
弗伦迪先生，您的欧洲之行
一定有不少非凡的经历吧
Say, Mr. Ferrante, you must have
had some wonderful experiences in Europe.
是的
Yes.
- 那么，能不能请您多谈几句呢？  - 不行
- Well, would you care to expand that statement?  - No.
哦
Oh.
我要问的问题实在是太多了…
There are so
many questions...
哦，弗伦迪和你在同一条船上是吗？
Oh, I forgot Ferrante was on
the same boat with you, wasn't he?
- 你说的对  - 跟他认识了？
- Yes, he was.  - Did you meet him?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
- 他潇洒吗？  - 嗯哼
- Was he charming?  - Mm-hmm.
嗯，我肯定尼基…
Well, I'm sure Nickie has all...
他迷人吗？
Fascinating?
- 很好，好，噢，噢  - 嗯哼
- Well, good, oh, oh.  - Mm-hmm.
- 对，我们在这方面没什么危机…  - 不可抗拒吗？
- Well, you know, financial difficulties often cause...
- Irresistible?
- 婚姻解体…  - 哦，对不起
- The breakup of marriages...  - Oh, I'm sorry.
- 我敢肯定不会是你的一个…  - 我太多心了
- I'm sure that won't be one of your...  - That wasn't like me.
- 我收回刚才的话  - 那不是我们的难题
- I withdraw that remark.  - That won't be one of our difficulties.
那么，请问，弗伦迪先生
您是不是第一次过伉俪生活呢？
Well, tell me, Mr. Ferrante, is this
your first experience with connubial bliss?
您能不能再说一遍？
Would you mind
rephrasing the question?
噢，亲爱的！
Oh, darling!
他的意思是问你是不是第一次结婚？
He means is this your
first experience with marriage?
- 哦，是这意思  - 是的
- Oh, that's what he meant. - Yes.
呃，很好，您是否按您太太习惯的…
Uh, good. Do you intend
to support your wife in the...
- 方式供养她…  - 是的
- uh, manner to which, uh...  - Yes.
- 真有意思  - 怎么供养？
- That's very funny.  - Doing what?
我打算…我打算重新开始画画
Well, I'm... I'm going to begin
to paint again.
靠卖画来供养我妻子
That's how I intend
to support my wife.
哦，是吗…
Oh, well...
那你可得多准备点儿…颜料
That's certainly going to take
an awful lot of... paint.
呃…我是说你们已经满屋子都是稀世名画了
I mean, you already have
a house full of masterpieces.
说得对，再说我没料到
你会有这样的打算…
Yes, we have, and I didn't realize
that you were going to...
- 反正我要画画  - 哦，是吗？
- I'm still going to paint.  - Oh, really?
我是说你不是早就不画了吗？
Well, I mean, I just thought
you'd given all that up.
是的，我不该放弃
I know,
but I shouldn't have.
- 哦，不过我相信尼基一定有其他什么打算  - 我是有
- Well, I'm sure Nickie has all kinds of plans.  - Yes, I have.
哦，那好，呃，你们准备什么时候结婚？
Well, good.
When are you going to be married?
- 我们商定，只要…  - 等一等，亲爱的
- We're going to be married as soon as we...  - Just a moment, dear.
六个月以后
In six months.
六个月，克拉克小姐肯定结不成婚
Six months. I'll bet
she never gets him to the altar.
六个月以后，那好
Uh, six months.
Well, good.
非常感谢，克拉克小姐
哦，还有您，弗伦迪先生
Thank you so much, Miss Clarke,
and, uh, you, too, Mr. Ferrante.
各位观众，我们对这对佳人的采访就到此为止
Well, folks, that winds up our interview
with this charming couple.
- 特瑞？  - 嗯哼
- Terry?  - Mm-hmm.
我想再问你一次
I'd like to ask
that question again.
你觉得弗伦迪真的不可抗拒吗？
Did you find
Ferrante irresistible?
哦…哦，肯，真对不起
Oh... Oh, Ken, I'm sorry.
有些…有些没料到的事却偏巧发生了！
You... You don't plan these things.
They just happen!
亲爱的，你这样也太荒唐了
Darling, it just
doesn't make sense.
我知道是很荒唐
I know.
I know it doesn't.
- 你应该现实一点儿  - 在爱情上吗？
- You've got to be realistic.  - About love?
别人怎么议论他知道吗？
But you know what
everyone says about him.
知道，我知道，知道，我知道
Yes, I know,
I know, I know.
- 你打算怎么办？  - 噢，我不知道，肯
- What are you going to do?  - Oh, I don't know, Ken.
我…我还是…
I... I think I'll...
我还是回波士顿
我可以找份工作…
I think I'll go back to Boston
and try and get a job or something...
或是还去唱歌 直到他能…
in singing again until he can...
直到他什么？
Until he what?
亲爱的，他永远也养不活你
Darling, he'll never
be able to support you.
噢，特瑞，你听我说，我打算娶你
Oh, Terry, listen to me.
I want to marry you.
我知道我早该向你求婚的
I know I should have
asked you a long time ago.
这都怪我，可现在还不晚，是吗？特瑞
It's my fault, but it's not too late, is it?
It can't be too late.
特瑞，看着我
Terry, look at me.
我爱你知道吗？
Can't you see I'm in love?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
可我爱他
So am I.
你看能卖掉吗？
Well, do you think
you can sell it?
当然，我可以试试
Of course, I'll try.
- 你画这个没请模特吗？  - 没有，我请不起
- You did this without a model?  - Yeah, I couldn't afford one.
怎么啦？
我的记忆出毛病了？
What is it?
Something wrong with my memory?
- 我觉得情绪有点儿低落  - 哪里
- It's getting a trifle dim.  - No.
- 这个也是？  - 哦，凭我的记忆画的，这是我的午餐
- And this?  - Oh, I painted that from memory.
That was my lunch.
- 一幅女人的肖像  - 知道
- You know, it's a woman.  - Yes.
和她一起不怕被看见？
You mean, you wouldn't
care to be seen with her?
不一定
I doubt it.
尼基，如果你让我告诉她们…
You know, Nickie,
if you would let me tell people...
告诉那些女顾客你的尊姓大名的话…
By people, I mean women...
who painted this...
那么有多少…有多少就能卖多少
I could sell it
and plenty more.
不不不，过去的弗伦迪已经死了
No, no, no.
The old Ferrante is dead.
可你这罗基的笔名一钱不值
But signing "Rossi"
don't mean a thing.
- 应该用你的真名字…  - 过去的弗伦迪已经死了…
- If you use your own name...  - The old Ferrante is dead...
新的罗基正在挨饿
and the new Rossi is starving.
你想在三个月之内就打响吗？
What do you expect
in three months?
别忘了，画笔听手的指挥
Remember, the brush
obeys your hand.
它可不知道你已经习惯我行我素了
It doesn't know you are
accustomed to getting your own way.
习惯到处受宠，画笔并不知道这些
You are spoiled,
but the brush doesn't know this.
它可不会哄你
He cannot humor you.
这我知道
不过我希望能卖掉一幅
I know, I know, but I was
hoping you'd sell something.
我想尝尝挣钱的滋味
I want the thrill
of earning that first dollar.
- 哦，看来我只能找份活干了  - 什么？
- Oh, well, I'll have to get a job.  - What?
你想放弃绘画？
And give up painting?
不，我不会放弃
除了画画我不会别的
No, I'm not going to give up painting.
It's the only thing I know.
但我要挣钱，挣一大笔钱
而且还要快
But I've got to earn money.
I've got to earn a lot of it quickly.
那当然，这段时间我给你买午饭
Of course, in the meantime,
I'll buy you lunch.
等你出了名再把钱还给我
You can repay me
when you're famous.
这是你第一句鼓励我的话
That's the first
encouraging thing you've said.
- 穿上吧  - 太动人了
- There you are.  - Isn't that extraordinary?
我的记忆没出毛病你说是吗？
Wouldn't you think
that's the one thing I could remember?
- 是的  - 嗯哼
- Yeah.  - Hmm.
噢，好吧
Hmph. Oh, well.
（波士顿司迈特俱乐部 隆重推荐特瑞小姐）
♪ 我们将在彩云上散步 ♪
# We'll be walking on clouds #
（特瑞·麦凯）
♪ 你的烦恼 ♪
# You'll forget every care #
♪ 就像泡泡 ♪
# And your troubles like bubbles #
♪ 消失在那 ♪
# Will vanish #
♪ 空气里 ♪
# In air #
♪ 你问我如何 ♪
# Ask me how do you get #
♪ 到达明日乐园 ♪
# To Tomorrow Land #
♪ 只要闭上眼睛 ♪
# Close your eyes #
♪ 许下夙愿 ♪
# Make a wish #
♪ 你就到了 ♪
# And you're there #
♪ 是要闭上眼睛 ♪
# Close your eyes #
♪ 许下夙愿 ♪
# Make a wish #
♪ 你就 ♪
# And you're #
♪ 到了 ♪
# There ##
尼基！尼基！
Nickie! Nickie!
- 嘿！  - 嘿！
- Hey!  - Hey!
我带来了好消息
我卖掉了你的一个女人
I have good news!
I sold one of your women.
就是那个身穿……咹
You know, the one
with the uh-huh.
我把它卖了200美元
I got $200 for her.
这是你的第一笔收入！
Your first dollar!
我说你这是怎么啦？
What's the matter with you?
我的朋友，我太快活了
我是个画家
My friend, I'm a happy man.
I am a painter.
那又怎么样？
我都画了几十年了，可一点儿都不快活
So what? I've been a painter for years,
but I ain't happy.
哦，是吗
Oh, well.
谢谢，谢谢女士们先生们
Thank you. Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
这是我最后一个晚上…
As you know,
this is my last night...
我要放声歌唱 把我心中的歌献给大家
so I would love to sing a song for you
that is very close to my heart.
♪ 我们的爱情 ♪
# Our love affair #
♪ 很是奇妙 ♪
# Is a wondrous thing #
♪ 我们很高兴地 ♪
# That we'll rejoice #
♪ 留在记忆里 ♪
# In remembering #
♪ 我们的爱情与生俱来 ♪
# Our love was born #
♪ 第一次拥抱就恋上 ♪
# With our first embrace #
♪ 撕开那 ♪
# And a page was torn #
♪ 时空的扉页 ♪
# Out of time and space #
♪ 愿我们的爱情 ♪
# Our love affair #
♪ 就像是那 ♪
# May it always be #
♪ 永恒燃烧的 ♪
# A flame to burn #
♪ 炽热火焰 ♪
# Through eternity #
♪ 那么牵着我的手 ♪
# So take my hand #
♪ 让我们热情地祷告 ♪
# With a fervent prayer #
♪ 我们能够共同生活 ♪
# That we may live #
♪ 一起分享 ♪
# And we may share #
♪ 爱情的喜悦 ♪
# A love affair #
♪ 请记住啊 ♪
# To remember #
♪ 这段永志难忘的爱情 ♪
# A love affair #
♪ 请你 ♪
# To #
♪ 记住 ♪
# Remember ##
- 安全带系好了吗？  - 嗯，系好了
- Did you fasten your seat belt?  - Mm-hmm. It's fastened.
- 那就是帝国大厦  - 谢谢
- There's the Empire State Building.  - Thank you.
噢！欢迎！
Ah! Welcome!
- 啊！  - 麦凯小姐，亲爱的
- Ah!  - Miss McKay, my dear.
- 我最喜爱的顾客，欢迎您回来  - 太谢谢你了
- My favorite customer, welcome back.  - Thank you.
- 韦布小姐，看看谁来了  - 啊，麦凯小姐
- Miss Webb, look who's back.  - Well, Miss McKay.
我们正说您呐：“麦凯小姐怎么不来呢？”
We were just saying,
"Whatever happened to Miss McKay?"
瞧您，真来了
And here you are.
- 您的衣服真漂亮  - 是的，我知道，不是在这儿买的
- How nice you're looking.  - Yes, I know, I didn't get it here.
- 这半年你都到哪儿去了？  - 在波士顿
- Where have you been these past months?  - In Boston.
- 哦？我们可真想您  - 谢谢，我也想你们 你姓……
- Oh? Well, we've missed you.  - I've missed you, too, Miss, uh...
- 纳恩  - 哦对，纳恩小姐
- Lane.  - Yes, Miss Lane.
纳恩小姐，我想买件非常非常漂亮的衣服…
Now, Miss Lane, I want something
very, very special for...
那好，让韦布小姐帮您挑，麦凯小姐
Miss Webb will be very happy
to take care of you, Miss McKay.
我去办公室有事，失陪了
Excuse me.
I have something to do in the office.
- 没关系  - 我非常愿意为您效劳，麦凯小姐
- All right.  - Well, of course, I'd be
most happy to take care of you.
您打算要件什么样的？
Now, what did you
have in mind?
要穿上去很有魅力，又不太贵
而且还是粉色的
Well, I want something
irresistible, inexpensive and... pink.
噢，这很容易！我们有货
Oh, but, of course!
We have it.
最漂亮的 我给您留了一件
The most beautiful.
I've been hiding it just for you.
只要店里有
麦凯小姐要什么就给她什么
I tell you, you give Miss McKay
anything in the shop she wants.
不过你要留住她我马上就去，懂吗？
But keep talking to her
until I get there, will you?
这我们就放心了
That's all we wanted to know.
那好，哦，你是不是担心我不付钱啦？
Fine. Say, you weren't
worried about her credit, were you?
想到哪儿去了，再见
I'm surprised at you. Good-bye.
- 这件相当迷人  - 我穿短了点儿
- This is adorable.  - It's a little short, isn't it?
- 哦，配上这个  - 噢，不行
- Oh, with these.  - Oh, no.
噢，你看看，这件最合适了
Oh, but look. Look!
This is a must.
是挺不错的
可我就想要我选中的那件粉色的
Yes, it's lovely, but I just want
the little item I decided on.
好吧，我们送去
All right, we'll send it.
我回头通知你们地址
我现在还不知道我住哪儿
I'll have to let you know where,
because I'm not quite sure.
- 数一数对不对  - 怎么不记帐了？
- I believe that's right.  - No, uh, no charge?
- 不  - 不记？
- No.  - No?
不，我知道，不过我不记了…
No. I know, I know, but... no.
- 啊，肯！  - 特瑞，你好
- Why, Ken!  - Terry. How are you?
你怎么到这儿来了？
你怎么知道我…
What are you doing here?
How did you know I...
啊哈，明白了
生意做得真周到
Uh-huh, I see.
Nice doing business with you.
噢，对不起，肯，我恐怕已经晚了
Oh, forgive me, Ken.
I'm terribly late.
- 现在几点了？  - 哦，现在是差五分五点
- What time is it?  - It's, uh, five minutes to 5:00.
噢！噢，见到你我太高兴了，肯
Oh! Oh, it's been good
seeing you, Ken.
我也很高兴，特瑞
要说的话太多了
It's good seeing you, too, Terry.
There's so much to talk to you about.
实在对不起，我有点儿急事
I'm sorry,
but I'm in such a hurry.
- 我们找地方喝一杯吧？  - 不行，我真的有急事
- Can't we go someplace and have a cocktail?  - I really am in a hurry.
- 我有很多话要说  - 这样吧你可以打个电话…
- But I have so much to say to you.  - Why don't you give me a call...
噢，不行，不能打，因为我要接…
You can't do that,
because I'm getting marr...
- 要结婚？  - 是的，我要结婚了，肯，我已经来迟了
- You're getting married?  - Yes. Yes, I am, Ken, and I'm very, very late.
- 你刚才说几点了？  - 哦，差四分五点
- What time did you say it was?  - Uh, four minutes to 5:00.
- 啊，再见了，肯  - 特瑞
- Well, good-bye, Ken.  - Terry.
我忠心地希望你能找到幸福…
I really hope
you've found happiness...
万一你需要帮忙…
and if you're ever
in need of anything...
需要有人爱你，尽管跟我打电话
like someone to love you,
don't hesitate to call me.
不，我不需要，再见了，肯
No. No, I won't.
Good-bye, Ken.
再见，祝你好运
Good-bye. Good luck.
我真是急糊涂了
Shows what a state I'm in.
以为帝国大厦在那边
当然是在这边儿！
I thought the Empire State Building
was this way, and, of course, it's that way!
我就在这儿下车吧，我有点儿急事
I think I'll get out here,
because I'm in a hurry.
- 给你，别找钱了  - 急什么呀小姐？
- Here you are. Keep the change.  - What's the rush, lady?
你知道，我马上就要结婚了
我想让你第一个来祝贺我
I'm going to be married, and I want you
to be the first to congratulate me.
- 谢谢  - 去结婚也不该这么急啊
- Thank you.  - Marriage is somethin' to rush to?
102层
102nd floor.
（5点）
- 下去吗？  - 呃，不下，谢谢
- Going down?  - No. No, thank you.
到了
Tower.
- 您下去吗？  - 不下，几点了？
- Going down?  - No, no. And what time have you?
- 五点过十分  - 哦，谢谢
- Ten after 5:00.  - Oh. Thank you.
（7点）
我知道该干什么，我要走自己的路！
I know what I'm doing.
I want my own way!
快调转船头！
Turn the boat around!
我要你调转船头
I... I want to turn
the boat around.
噢，尼基，帮我把船头调过来
Oh, Nickie, help me
turn the boat around.
你比我…你比我的劲儿大多了
Well, you're so...
You're so much stronger than I am.
我一个人不行，我不行…
I can't do it alone.
I can't...
- 嘘  - 我不行
- Shh.  - I can't.
- 你现在需要安静  - 可我…我需要他！
- You must be quiet now.  - But... But I need him!
噢，尼基，我需要你！
Oh, Nickie, I need you!
帮帮我！帮帮我！
Help me! Help me!
帮我把船头调过来
Help me turn
the boat around.
我…我必须把船调过来
I... I must...
I must... aah.
您下吗？
Going down?
X光片结果不太乐观
Her X-rays aren't
very encouraging.
她能否走路还很难说
It's hard to say
if she'll ever walk again.
得过很长时间才能知道
We won't know
for a long while.
这可…太遗憾了
That's... That's bad.
您大概已经知道 他喊叫的人不是我
I guess you've gathered by now
I'm not the man she was screaming about.
她正准备去结婚
She was on her way
to marry him.
- 他知道这消息吗？  - 不
- Does he know of her condition?  - No.
她说 在你们能否确认她康复之前…
She said until you know
what you say you won't know for a while...
她不想让他知道
she'd rather he didn't know.
- 她是个好姑娘  - 是啊，我有同感
- She seems nice.  - I... I think so.
她想见你
She wants to see you.
去吧，我一会儿就来
Go ahead.
I'll be in shortly.
- 你好，肯  - 你好，特瑞
- Hello, Ken.  - Hello, Terry.
我告诉她我不知道她能否活过今天
I told her I didn't know whether or not
she'd be with us today.
你骗我的，神父
Fooled you, Father.
肯，我把你和我事告诉了神父
Ken, I told
Father McGrath about us.
他答应帮我找个工作，是吗，神父？
He's going to find me a job,
aren't you, Father?
- 你还是先把身体养好，特瑞  - 他说得对
- You'd better get well first, Terry.  - He's right.
- 然后我再帮你找工作  - 嗯哼
- Then I'll try and come up with something.  - Hmm. Oh.
- 先别着急  - 好吧
- Take it easy.  - Yes.
尼古拉先生
Monsieur Nicolo.
这是夫人留下的 先生
我正要给您寄去
[French]
她叮嘱要留给麦凯小姐
Pour Miss McKay.
- 跟您来过的那姑娘  - 谢谢，马瑞阿斯
- [French]  - Merci, Marius.
先生 您要在这儿住几天吗？
[French]
- 我还没定下来  - 哦，那好，先生
- [French]  - [French]
- 麦凯小姐？  - 什么事？
- Miss McKay?  - Yes?
谢谢您这么热心地帮助我的儿子蒂龙
I want to thank you
for what you're doin' for my son Tyrone.
他不会成为我这样的笨人了
Now he won't grow up
to be a mug like me.
- 你太谦虚了，巴哥斯先生  - 哦，不是谦虚
- You're too modest, Mr. Bugsy.  - Oh, no, I ain't.
我这人笨得连字都不识几个 太谢谢了
I'm so stupid,
I ain't even ignorant. Thanks again.
不要谢谢我，要谢麦格拉思神父
Don't thank me.
Thank Father McGrath.
- 是他让我来的  - 谢谢，神父
- He got the job for me.  - Thanks, Father.
大家注意了
All eyes on me, please.
你们都知道小莫莉得了风疹
我来代她唱
Now, as you know, poor Mollie
has the measles, so I'll sing her part.
准备好了吗？
Now, are we ready?
哦
Oh.
好，现在准备好了
Well, uh, now we're ready.
注意我的手势
一定不能出错
Watch me closely.
We mustn't goof today.
♪ 有个小小童军 ♪
# They say there's
a tiny little scout #
♪ 跟你到处行走 ♪
# Who follows you about #
♪ 你的言行举止 他都知道 ♪
# He knows everything
you say and do #
♪ 你无法将他甩掉 ♪
# You couldn't lose him
if you wanted to #
♪ 他可无所不知 假如你要 ♪
# He knows, like for instance when you try #
♪ 口是心非 ♪
# To tell a big, fat lie #
♪ 他会将你的谎言曝光 ♪
# He starts burnin'up at what you said #
♪ 于是你定将面红耳赤 ♪
# That's why your face gets red #
♪ 假如你和他一起行善 ♪
# When you do good like he says you should #
♪ 他会像小丑一样开心 ♪
# You can bet he' as merry as a clown #
♪ 但你做了亏心事 你的心儿怦怦跳 ♪
# But when you've done somethin'
and your heart starts thumpin' #
♪ 那就是他在你的心上蹦跳 ♪
# That's him jumpin' up and down #
♪ 他随时伴在你的身旁 解开你的疑惑 ♪
# He's there anytime that you're in doubt #
♪ 教你如何处世 ♪
# To tell you what to do #
♪ 变得更加聪明 ♪
# Get smart #
♪ 听听小小童军的声音 ♪
# Listen to the tiny scout #
♪ 他懂你的心情和环境 ♪
# He knows you inside He knows you outside #
♪ 他知道所有的世间事 ♪
# He knows what it's all about #
- ♪ 毫无疑问 ♪  - ♪ 你里里外外他最清楚 ♪
- # Without a doubt #  - # He knows you inside out #
♪ 你讨厌参加主日学 ♪
# So you hate to go to Sunday school #
♪ 其实这又能算个啥 ♪
# And that's not bad enough #
♪ 你起初调皮又捣蛋 ♪
# You start messin' with the Golden Rule #
♪ 却以为乖乖很女生 ♪
# You think bein'good is sissy stuff #
♪ 别耍聪明要改过 ♪
# Get wise, try to mend
your dopey ways #
♪ 心怀坦荡真快乐 ♪
# Ya might be glad ya did #
♪ 从此远离坏杂念 ♪
# Then you'll never hear the corny phrase #
♪ 糊涂可怜的傻小子 ♪
# Poor little mixed-up kid #
♪ 流言蜚语让你伤心 ♪
# When you prove you can't be trusted
you can say you're maladjusted #
♪ 怨爹怨妈你可怜虫 ♪
# You can blame your ma and pa
if you're a schmo #
♪ 怪罪他人的胆小鬼 ♪
# But you show a streak of yeller
when you blame the other feller #
- ♪ 注意咯 ♪  - ♪ 你们或许唧唧喳 ♪
- # Look out #  - # You may sizzle down below #
♪ 别去做老师的马屁精 ♪
# You don't have to be a teacher' pet #
♪ 别去担心翅膀不发芽 ♪
# Don't worry wings won't sprout Just get smart #
♪ 听听小小童军的声音 ♪
# Listen to the tiny scout #
♪ 他懂你的心情和环境 ♪
# He knows you inside
He knows you outside #
♪ 你站错边 他站对边 ♪
# You're on the wrong side He's on the right side #
♪ 他知道你退步 他知道你进步 ♪
# He knows you backwards He knows you forwards #
♪ 你找麻烦 他来收拾 ♪
# You're on the mean side He's on the clean side #
哇！♪ 我快不能呼吸 ♪
Whew! # I'm runnin' out of breath #
- ♪ 快别吸烟 ♪  - ♪ 你说好哎好哎 ♪
- Stop smokin'! - #You're sayin' yes, yes #
♪ 他却说不行 ♪
# He's sayin' uh-uh #
♪ 你认为必须 他叫你打住 ♪
# You think you've got to He tells you not to #
♪ 他与你形影相随 事事进言 ♪
# He's there beside you all set to guide you #
♪ 拉赫 拉赫 拉赫噻 咚咚呛 ♪
# Rah, rah, rah sis, boom, bah #
♪ 瑞吉，醍吉，醍安，你们别吹嘘 ♪
# Ricky, ticky, tin and a ricky ticky tout #
♪ 多么微小的小童军
你里里外外他最清楚 ♪
# How about a cheer for the tiny scout
'cause he knows you inside out #
♪ 好、坏、肮脏、干净 ♪
# Good side, bad side
clean side, mean side #
♪ 错、对、内在、外在 ♪
# Wrong side, right side
outside, inside #
♪ 毫无疑问他是你朋友 ♪
# He's your friend without a doubt #
♪ 他是你的益友 ♪
# He's your conscience #
♪ 他是你的良知 ♪
# He knows you #
♪ 里边 ♪
# Inside #
♪ 外边 ♪
# Out ##
谁呀，快进来！
Well! Come in!
- 尼基，见到你真高兴  - 我的老朋友！
Nickie, I'm so happy to see you.
My dear friend!
快进来，快坐
Come in. Come in. Come in.
- 最坏的评论是什么？  - 啊，你就等着瞧吧
- How's my severest critic?  - Ah, well, we'll see.
你都把画排好了
来吧，都讲给我听听
I see you've got them all arranged.
Come on. Let me hear the worst.
六个月的成果
你的时间总算没有白费，尼基
Six months' work.
You haven't wasted your time, Nickie.
谢谢，你不知道我都扔了五十幅了
Thank you. You should have seen the 50
I dropped over the cliff though.
也许你应该把这幅画也扔掉
Maybe you should have
dropped this one too.
对，你这个主意我倒是同意
Yes, I'm inclined to agree
with you about that one.
- 得了，你画这几幅画的时候
我知道你在想些什么  - 是吗？
- I can read your state of mind
when you painted this.  - Yeah?
你画这幅画的时候心里难过极了
You were very sorry for yourself
when you painted this one.
- 那张画是我八月份画的，别谈了  - 嗯
- That one was painted in August. Doesn't count.  - Hmm!
画这张画时心里很气恼
破碎的心被气愤挫败了
You were angry here.
You were getting over your broken heart.
- 破碎的心？噢，我的心什么时候破碎过  - 没碎就更好
- Broken heart? Oh, that stuff's not for me.  - I'm glad to hear that.
- 还是谈谈这边几幅吧  - 我这就谈
- Come on. Let's get down to this end. Come on.  - I'm coming to that.
咱们马上就谈
I'm coming to that.
你瞧，尼基，你成为真正的画家了
Yeah, here, Nickie,
you became a painter.
谢谢，我也觉得这幅画画得还可以
Thank you. I'm not exactly
ashamed of that one myself.
我要说的千言万语全都画在上面了
I had a great deal to say,
and I painted it instead.
长时间地远离家乡
那种孤独和寂寞给人以启迪，使得你…
Your being away, alone, for a long time,
has given you that grasp of...
我来接，记住刚才的话茬
I'll get it. Remember where you were.
一会儿接着说
I want to hear more of that.
喂？我是科尔曼颜料商店
Hello? Courbet's
Paint and Varnish Store.
尼基？我听说你今天回来了
Nickie? I read
you arrived today.
洛伊斯，是你呀，你怎么知道我在这儿？
Lois, how nice.
How did you know I was here?
我打到你的饭店
他们说你可能在这儿
I called your hotel, and they said
you could be reached at this number.
噢，尼基，我天天都在想你
早上，中午，晚上…
Oh, Nickie, I've been thinking about you
morning, noon and night...
时时刻刻都在想
and in-between times too.
我想知道你能不能和我…
I was wondering
if maybe you could...
呃，恐怕…呃，不行，不行
这主意倒是不错，我很感激
Aha. Well... Oh, no, no,
I like the idea all right.
不过我下午可能没有时间
That's a nice offer, but I don't think
I can make it this afternoon.
嗯，要是你来不了的话…
噢，要是能来该多好
Well, if you can't do that...
Oh, I wish you would.
嗯
Mmm-mmm.
非常感谢，谢谢你的盛情邀请
Thanks anyway. Nicest thing
that's happened today.
哦，那你晚上来看芭蕾好吗
Oh. But you could
make the show tonight.
我把你的票留在售票处
Well, I'll leave a ticket
at the box office anyway.
一定来吧
还有，尼基！
Do try to make it.
And, Nickie!
不管有什么事
把看完芭蕾以后的时间留给我？呵
Whatever you do, don't plan anything
for after the show, huh?
- 位子真不错  - 什么？
- I love our seats.  - What?
我说我们的位子真不错
I said I love our seats.
- 这场芭蕾真不错  - 谢谢您的邀请
- We enjoyed it very much.  - Thank you for asking us.
噢，我很愿意，不介意的话
弗伦迪先生要送我回去了
Oh, it was a pleasure. If you don't mind,
Mr. Ferrante will see me home.
- 那好吧，晚安  - 晚安
- Very well. Good night.  - Good night.
- 晚安  - 晚安
- Good night.  - Good night.
- 你想去哪儿？  - 你来决定吧，尼基
- Now, where would you like to go?  - Suppose you decide, Nickie.
确切地说这是你的晚上
After all,
this is your evening.
我离开的时间太长了
不知道现在人们爱去哪儿
I've been away so long
I have no idea where people go nowadays.
我的大衣
My coat.
你好
Hello.
特瑞，让我告诉他吧
Terry, please let me tell him.
噢，不，不能
Oh, no. No.
- 我去叫住他  - 不，千万别去，求你了，肯
- I'll go get him.  - No, please. Please, Ken.
真难为你了
It's pretty rough.
今天是你第一次出来
可偏偏碰见了他
The first time you're able to get out,
and you have to run into him.
我也只能说一声“你好”
And all I could
say was hello.
好了，戏演完了
Well, the show's over.
小伙子得到了姑娘，走吧？
Boy got the girl.
Shall we go?
请稍等一下
I'll only be a minute.
嗯
Yes.
晚安，洛伊斯，谢谢
Good night, Lois,
and thank you.
今天晚上我不应该
带你去那儿看芭蕾，是吗？
Taking you to a show tonight
wasn't a very good idea, was it?
- 圣诞快乐，洛伊斯  - 圣诞快乐，尼基，再见
- Merry Christmas, Lois.
- Merry Christmas, Nickie, and... auf Wiedersehen.
唉，别人这时候都出去狂欢…
Oh, I think it's terrible
to have to take you home...
你却叫我带你回家
不太合适吧
just when everyone else
is going out.
可…这就是我的生活
Tsk. C'est la vie,
et cetera.
特瑞，我再问你一遍
Terry, let me ask you again.
为什么不让我来帮助你？
Why won't you
let me help you?
那好吧，我就再回答你一遍
All right then,
I will tell you again.
如果你花钱为我治病，他会不高兴的
Now, if you paid for my getting well,
he wouldn't like it.
如果他不高兴，我也会不高兴
And if he didn't like it,
I wouldn't like it.
如果你给我治好了
我跑去找他，你又会不高兴
Then if you did get me well,
and I went to him, you wouldn't like it.
至少应该让他知道
But certainly
he ought to know.
不，如果他了知道我这样
他肯定会设法为我付医疗费…
No, because if he found out,
he'd insist upon doing it himself...
可他到哪儿去弄钱呢
if he had the money,
which I doubt.
万一我再恢复不了，噢，那可太残酷了
And then if I didn't get well, ooh!
That'd be awful.
不行，当我能走路那天…
我能跑向他的时候，我再告诉他
No, unless I can walk to him... and when
I say walk, I mean run... he'll never know.
我能自理，我有个工作
又赚了一些钱
Well, I'm fine.
I've got my job, and I'm on a budget.
如果治疗顺利的话
如果我能完好如初…
If things come out right,
and then maybe if I'm a very good girl...
下一个圣诞节我就能如愿了
I'll get what
I want next Christmas.
明白吗？
Follow?
- 圣诞快乐  - 圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas.  - Merry Christmas.
你感觉怎么样，麦凯小姐？
How are you feeling,
Miss McKay?
孩子们，告诉你们一个坏消息
Children, I have
bad news for you.
- 医生不准我跟你们去  - 哦！
- Doctor won't let me go with you.  - Oh!
医生 我两小时以后就回来
I could be back
in a couple of hours.
他们要参加圣诞义演
也是他们第一次登台演出
他们是我的队员
This is the Christmas benefit. This is their
first public appearance. This is my team.
- 她是我们的教练，大夫  - 诺曼，医生
- She's our coach, Doc.  - Norman, Doctor.
她是我们的教练，医生
She's our coach, Doctor.
对她身体不利的事
你们不会让她做的，对吗？
If it wasn't good for her,
you wouldn't want her to go, would you?
对！
No!
这样吧，你们自己去唱怎么样？
Well, look, why don't
you try it without me?
- 嗯  - 勇敢点儿
- Mmm.  - Come on.
只不过开头有点儿困难
The only thing that would bother you
would be the start.
- 麦凯小姐？  - 说吧，蒂龙
- Miss McKay?  - Yes, Tyrone?
我们唱歌的时候心里会想着你…
We'll be thinking about you
while we're singing...
愿你早日把身体养好
hoping that you'll be
around okay real soon.
噢，谢谢，蒂龙
Oh, thank you, Tyrone.
等一等，萨利在哪儿？她今天怎么没来？
Wait a minute. Where's Sally?
Isn't she with us today?
- 我们把她开除了，她声音老冒尖  - 她老爱出风头
- We took her off the team.
She sings too loud.  - She's a show-off.
萨利说她是开玩笑
她天天盼着登台演出
Sally thought it was a joke,
and she wanted so badly to go on the stage.
噢！过来，亲爱的
Oh! You come
here, darling.
听着，你可以跟小伙伴上台演出
Now, you go right up on the stage
with the rest of them.
我准许你回来
但是你得保证唱歌时绝对不许再冒高调儿了
I'll put you back on the team,
but you must promise not to
drown out the other children.
好，我保证，麦凯小姐
All right, Miss McKay.
- 好 准备好了吗？  - 准备好了
- Now, are we ready?  - Yes.
唱一遍
All right.
♪ 有个奇妙的地方 ♪
# There's a wonderful place #
♪ 叫做明日乐园 ♪
# Called Tomorrow Land #
♪ 明日乐园 ♪
# Tomorrow Land #
♪ 它是个遥远的梦乡 ♪
# And it' only a dream away #
♪ 遥远 ♪
# Away #
♪ 当你去到 ♪
# And the moment you get #
♪ 那明日乐园 ♪
# To Tomorrow Land #
♪ 明日乐园 ♪
# Tomorrow Land #
♪ 你会忘了今天的一切 ♪
# You'll forget all about #
- ♪ 今天 ♪  - ♪ 今天 ♪
- # Today # - # Today #
♪ 你将漫步在云端 ♪
# You'll be walking
on clouds #
♪ 忘却所有的忧愁 ♪
# You'll forget every care #
♪ 你的烦恼就像泡泡 ♪
# And your troubles like bubbles #
♪ 消失在空气里 ♪
# Will vanish in air #
♪ 你问我如何去往 ♪
# Ask me how do you get #
♪ 那明日乐园 ♪
# To Tomorrow Land #
♪ 明日乐园 ♪
# Tomorrow Land #
♪ 只要闭上眼睛许下夙愿 ♪
# Close your eyes make a wish #
♪ 你就会抵达 ♪
# And you're there #
♪ 闭上你的眼睛 ♪
# Close your eyes #
♪ 许下你的夙愿 ♪
# Make a wish #
♪ 你就会 ♪
# And you're #
♪ 到那儿 ♪
# There ##
没有我，你们照样能唱好
You're going to do
all right without me.
好了好了，我们该走了，再见，特瑞
All right, children.
We must go now. Good-bye, Terry.
再见，神父
再见，亲爱的，去吧
Good-bye, Father.
Good-bye, darling. Run along.
圣诞快乐！
Merry Christmas! Bless you.
你要听话
Be good now.
哦
Oh.
圣诞快乐！
Merry... Christmas!
噢！圣诞快乐，亲爱的！
Oh! Merry Christmas, darling!
- 圣诞快乐！  - 噢
- Merry Christmas!  - Oh. Tsk.
这个圣诞你可不会怎么快乐，是吗？
This isn't going to
be much of a Christmas for you, is it?
- 这没什么  - 再放近点儿
- I'll be all right.  - There we are.
- 您能不能递给我那个…  - 当然可以
- Could you just hand me my...  - Yes, surely.
- 非常感谢  - 不客气
- Thank you so much.  - You're, uh...
我丈夫和我非常欢迎你
和我们一起去吃火鸡
Y-You're welcome to have
turkey with my husband and me.
请把火鸡腿给我留着好吗？
You save a drumstick for me
for later, will you?
好的，可以
All right, I will.
有什么事需要帮忙尽管喊我
And if there's anything else
you want, just holler.
太感谢您了，我会的
Thank you so much.
I will.
您待我太好了
圣诞快乐
It was very sweet of you.
Merry Christmas.
也祝你圣诞快乐
And a merry Christmas
to you too.
请问麦凯小姐是否…
Uh, does Miss McKay...
尼基？
Nickie?
你好，特瑞
Hello, Terry.
噢，这可…我真高兴
Oh, it's... g-g...
it's good to see you.
是呀，我也很高兴
It's good to see you too.
- 你不舒服吗？  - 没…没有，我感觉很好
- You feeling all right?  - Y-Yes. Yes. I'm fine.
- 我想休息一会儿  - 那好，那好，那好
- I'm just resting.  - Good, good. Good.
呃…很久没见了
Well, it's...
been a long time.
是啊，很久了
Yes, hasn't it?
我太高兴了
Well, it is good to see you.
你刚才说过了
You said that.
- 我可以…  - 哦，可以，请，坐吧
- May I, uh...  - Oh, yes, please, do. Sit down.
我一会儿就走，我想你不会介意
I'll only be a minute.
I'm sure you don't mind.
不，不，当然不
No, no, of course not.
噢，这儿的环境不错嘛？
Oh, is this
the breathtaking view?
就是位置高了一点儿
Well, the altitude
bothered me.
是啊
Yeah, yeah.
你一定…纳闷我怎么会找到这儿来
Well, I'll, uh, I'll bet
you're wondering how I got here.
是的，我是很纳闷
Well, yes. Yes, yes, I am.
是这样
我在电话薄上查一个叫麦基伯德的人
Well, I was, uh, I was looking
through a telephone book
for a man named McBride.
碰巧我发现了特·麦凯这个名字
And I, uh, I came across
the name T. McKay.
我对自己说“噢，这会不会是特瑞·麦凯…我的老朋友呢？”
And I said to myself,
"Oh, now, could that possibly be
Terry McKay, my old friend?"
- 还真是的  - 真是巧了
- And it was.  - Yes, yes.
然后我又对自己说…
And then I said to myself...
惭愧呀，我有点儿对不起麦凯小姐
"Well, now, I haven't been
very nice to Miss McKay.
我记得有一天我跟她约好要见面，可是我，我却没有赴约
After all, I had an appointment
with her one day, and, uh, I didn't keep it."
你没去赴约…
You didn't keep...
没有
No.
没去 所以我对自己说…
Well, so I said to myself...
我现在经常自言自语
I talk to myself
quite a lot these days.
我说我那样对待像麦凯小姐
这样的老朋友太不对了
I said, " Well, that's not a very nice way
to treat an old friend like Miss McKay.
我得向麦凯小姐道歉
I must apologize
to Miss McKay."
如果一个人失了约
他理应向对方道歉 对吗？
Don't you agree when someone doesn't keep
an appointment they should apologize?
对，噢，很对，我觉得你说得太对了
Yes. Oh, yes, I think
you're absolutely right.
我…我觉得失约的人…
I-I... Well, I-I think the least
people could do is...
起码应该向对方说一声对不起什么的
to say they're...
sorry or something.
所以我来了
So here I am.
你想得真周到
That's very sweet.
我应该来
I thought so.
我经常想起你
I've often wondered about you.
- 也惦记你怎么样啦  - 此话当真？
- And how you were.  - Did you really?
当然是真的
Yes, really.
哦，是啊，我也常想起你
Well, I... I've often
thought about you too.
那么，我没有去赴约你没生气吗？
Then, uh, then you weren't angry
because I wasn't there?
你当时一定很生气
I mean, you must
have been at first.
是的
Well, yes.
我是很气，我…
Yes, yes, I was.
我当时给气坏了
At first, I was furious.
我说道：“他怎么能这个样
竟然来耍弄我？”
I said, " He can't do this to me.
Who does he think he is?"
哦 你等了多久？
Hmph. How long
did you wait?
我是说你等了多久？
I mean, did you wait long?
呃，是的，我等了…
Uh, well, let's...
- 等了很久，我等啊
等啊，一直等到…  - 半夜
- Well, yes. Yes, I... I waited until about...  - Midnight.
哦
Oh.
然后你怎么办？
And then what did you do?
我那时简直气疯了 嗯
Well, then I got
really mad. Mmm.
你可以想象我孤零零地站在…
Well, you can imagine,
standing up there on the...
站在暴风雨里
Yes, in the thunderstorm.
In a thunderstorm.
你那会儿是怎么想的？
Then what did you say
to yourself?
我对自己说“算了，回家喝个一醉方休吧”
Well, then I said,
"Oh, go on home and get tight."
- 可你并没有喝醉  - 我没醉？
- But you didn't do that.  - Didn't I?
没有…
No. Well, uh...
我看，你可能是…
maybe just a little one...
每一个小时喝一点儿，喝一个来月
every hour
for about a month.
- 这能怨我吗？  - 哦，当然不能怨你
- Can you blame me?  - Oh, I should say not.
我起码应该写封信向你道歉
The least I could have done
was to have sent you a note.
也许等你想起来写的时候
我已经不知去向了
Well, perhaps by the time you thought of it,
you didn't know where to reach me.
你答应过我，我们再见面的时候你会问我
But you swore if you ever
saw me again you'd ask.
不对，不对
N-No. N-No.
我记得当时是说
如果可能你我都去赴约地点
I remember we said that if
we could make it, we'd be there.
如果一方没有赴约…
And if one of us
didn't show up...
那一定有充足的理由
it would be for
a darn good reason.
是这么说的吗？
Did we say that?
是的，我们确实是这么约定的
Yes, that... that is
exactly what we said.
你能详细地说说吗？
Well, like what for instance?
所以，既然这样，我不会再向你问什么了
So, there'll be no more
questions asked... I hope.
- 想抽支烟吗？  - 谢谢
- Would you like a cigarette?  - Thank you.
谢谢你，尼基
Thank you, Nickie.
这可真有意思？
Isn't that wonderful?
我赶到这儿来是为了…
I walked all the way
here just to...
可现在我连你为什么不去都不想问了
And now I'm not even supposed to ask you
why you weren't there.
你说怪不怪？
Isn't it strange?
我们两个曾经亲密无间
We used to read
each other's thoughts.
不一样了，是吗？
It's not the same, is it?
- 不太一样  - 呃
- Not quite.  - Hmph.
- 可看上去…  - 我知道
- It doesn't seem...  - I know.
不知是怎么回事，每当我…
I don't know what happens to me.
Whenever I...
没有结婚戒指
No wedding ring, I see.
- 没有  - 我还以为那位…
- No.  - Well, I thought at the...
昨晚剧院 那位？
Last night, the show?
他不是，他不过是，不是…
No, no.
He was just... No.
我不是故意冒犯你的
I didn't mean to offend you.
- 嗯  - 你的情况怎么样，尼基？
- Hmph.  - How's everything with you, Nickie?
- 噢，想起来问了？  - 嗯哼
- Oh, you can ask questions?  - Mm-hmm.
应该说昨晚碰见你之前
一切都还顺利
Well, I thought everything was fine
until I saw you last night.
我知道你我之间一定出现了隔阂…
Then I knew there must be
something between us...
说不定隔着大海
所以我就买了张船票
even if it's only an ocean,
so I bought myself a ticket.
哦，你要去旅行了？
Oh, you're... sailing?
今晚就走
Tonight.
- 你很快活是吗？  - 是的，是的
- And you're happy, aren't you?  - Yes, yes.
- 你呢？你怎么样？  - 不知道
- And you?  - I don't know.
我很担心将来
担心人们对我的议论
I'm worried about the future.
I don't know what people will think.
他们会说“他跑了，那个古怪的画家
They'll say,
"There he goes, the mad painter.
他准是中邪了
他不喜欢女人”
There's something the matter with him.
He doesn't like women."
- 人们为什么这么说呢？  - 为什么？
- Why would people say that?  - Why?
因为他走遍了全世界
每碰见一个女人他就问…
Because he sails the seven seas
and to every woman he meets he says...
“六个月以后你会在哪儿？”
"Where will you be
in six months?"
- 她们去赴约了吗？  - 都去了
- And they're there?  - Everywhere.
金字塔的塔尖 大教堂的顶楼 埃菲尔铁塔
Tops of pyramids, the domes
of cathedrals, the Eiffel Tower.
他约的地方越来越高
He still tries
to keep them up high.
- 而且总让姑娘白等  - 没错，等啊，等啊，等啊
- He keeps them waiting.  - Sure. Waiting, waiting, waiting.
这么长时间他在哪儿？
And where is he
all this time?
在等待
Waiting.
尼基，你不能老这样等待下去
But you can't
go on like that.
你不该这么做，哦，我真想说声你错了
It isn't right for you.
Oh, I wish I could say you were wrong.
我错过一次
I was once.
聊点儿别的怎么样？
How'd you like to
change the subject?
当然可以，我很愿意，圣诞快乐
Yes, yes, I'd love to.
Merry Christmas.
噢，我忘了这碴儿了
Oh, I almost forgot.
六个月前，谁能想到我们今天…
Now, six months ago,
who'd have thought...
会在温暖的壁炉前
共度圣诞节呢？
we'd be spending Christmas together
in front of a nice warm fire?
我给你带了件礼物
I brought you a present.
哦，谢谢…真抱歉，我没有礼物给你
Oh, thank you.
I... I'm sorry. I... don't have one for you.
我…我没想到会有今天
I... didn't think
I'd be seeing you.
我不是来要礼物的
这件也算不上圣诞礼物
That's all right. I didn't expect one.
That isn't really a Christmas present.
哦，难怪我的信都给退回来了
Oh, that's why
my letters came back.
我想把它寄给你
可我今天才知道你的地址
I would have sent it to you,
but I didn't know your address until today.
她想把它送给你，记得吗？
She wanted you
to have it, remember?
所以，呃，我就是为了这个才来的…
So, uh, well, that's
the, uh, reason I...
再见，特瑞
Good-bye, Terry.
再见，尼基
Good-bye, Nickie.
我画过你围着这披肩的肖像
You know, I painted you
like that with the shawl.
你看见该多好
库尔贝说那张画得最好了
I wish you could have seen it.
Courbet said it was one of my best.
我非常珍视它
I didn't think
I could ever part with it.
可是，永远留在身边又不太合适…
But, well, there was no reason
to keep it any longer, and, uh...
我舍不得把它卖掉
因为我…
I couldn't take money for it,
because, well, you know...
有一次，库尔贝说一位年轻的姑娘来到了画廊
她喜欢那幅画
So, uh, Courbet told me a young woman
came into the gallery, and, uh, she liked it.
她看出了那幅画的内涵
我就让库尔贝把画送给她了…
She saw in it what I'd hoped you'd see,
so I told Courbet to give it to her...
因为她说她没有钱，不仅没有钱而且是个…呃…
because, uh, he said she didn't have any money,
and not only that, she was, uh...
是个…
She was...
反正我让他把画送给她了
Anyway, I told him
to give it to her.
库尔贝说她很想要那幅画
噢，我说得太多了
Courbet said she wanted it so badly and,
uh, so I told him to give it to her.
可能是因为今天是圣诞节的缘故
You know, it's the, uh,
Christmas season and all that.
哦，你能理解我的心情
And, uh, you know me.
Holly in my heart.
亲爱的，别这么看着我
Darling, don't look
at me like that.
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
如果这种事不可避免
为什么偏偏是你？
If it had to happen to one of us,
why did it have to be you?
哦
Oh.
这不能怨别人，只怪我自己
It was nobody's fault
but my own.
我只顾仰望大厦了
I-I was looking up.
那是离上帝最近的地方
It was the nearest thing
to heaven.
你在上边
You were there.
噢，亲爱的，你别…别担心，亲爱的
Oh, darling, don't...
don't worry, darling.
如果你能画画，我就能走路
If you can paint, I can walk.
什么奇迹都能出现，对吗？
Anything can happen.
Don't you think?
对，亲爱的，对，对
Yes, darling, yes.
Yes, yes, yes.